<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Ebberon]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.ico</url><title>Ebberon</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:46:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:46:21 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>Aaron Percival</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Aundair]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Magical research, political intrigue, rural mysteries.<br><br>Welcome to Aundair, a land where magic flows as freely as the wine from its vineyards. Picture the charm of Harry Potter's Hogwarts spread across an entire nation. Here, the air is thick with enchantment, from the floating towers of Arcanix to the magical markets of Fairhaven. Adventurers will find themselves unraveling arcane mysteries, engaging in wizard duels, and navigating the sophisticated intrigues of high society. This is a place where knowledge is power, and the arcane arts hold sway over all.<br><br>Fairhaven<br><br>Aundair is home to a diverse population including humans, half-elves, elves, gnomes, and changelings. The people of Aundair are known for their intelligence, charisma, and magical prowess.<br><br>The creatures found in Aundair range from domesticated magical beasts and constructs to wild fey creatures in the untamed forests. Arcane experiments occasionally give rise to magical anomalies and rogue elementals.]]></description><link>session-1\regions\aundair.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session -1/Regions/Aundair.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:42:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Breland]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Urban adventures, espionage, frontier exploration.<br><br>Breland is a land of contrasts, where the sprawling countryside meets the towering cityscape of Sharn. Imagine a world that blends the neon-lit hustle of Cyberpunk 2077 with the noir mystery of The Wolf Among Us. In Sharn, the City of Towers, adventurers can lose themselves in the labyrinthine streets, unravel dark conspiracies in the shadowy undercity, or climb the social ladder amidst the glittering spires. This is a place where urban adventures abound, and every corner turned might reveal a new ally or a deadly foe.<br><br>Wroat<br><br>Breland boasts a rich tapestry of races including humans, halflings, dwarves, gnomes, and warforged. The cosmopolitan nature of Sharn attracts individuals from all across Khorvaire.<br><br>In Breland, you might encounter various urban creatures such as rat swarms and street thugs, as well as magical beings like gargoyles and invisible stalkers. The rural areas are home to more traditional threats like bandits and wild beasts.]]></description><link>session-1\regions\breland.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session -1/Regions/Breland.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:43:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Karrnath]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Military adventures, undead encounters, dark magic.<br><br>Karrnath is a nation hardened by war, where discipline and martial prowess are paramount. Imagine Game of Thrones meets The Walking Dead, with ancient fortresses and legions of undead soldiers. Adventurers might find themselves enlisted in military campaigns, defending against undead incursions, or uncovering the dark secrets that lie within Karrnath's crypts and battlefields. This is a land where honor and duty clash with dark magic and undead legions.<br><br>Korth<br><br>Karrnath is primarily inhabited by humans, but it also has significant populations of dwarves and elves. The nation is known for its strict military culture and its use of undead soldiers.<br><br>Karrnath's creatures include undead warriors, skeletal steeds, and necromantic horrors. The wilderness areas are home to dire wolves and other aggressive wildlife.]]></description><link>session-1\regions\karrnath.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session -1/Regions/Karrnath.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:43:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mournland (formerly Cyre)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Post-apocalyptic exploration, mysterious ruins, supernatural horrors.<br><br>The Mournland, formerly known as Cyre, is a land of eerie silence and haunting beauty. Imagine the oppressive atmosphere of Dark Souls, where every step into the mist could uncover a lost relic or a twisted monstrosity. The ruins of Metrol and other cities lie in wait, holding the secrets of the cataclysm that turned Cyre into a barren wasteland. Adventurers will face mutated creatures, navigate deadly magical anomalies, and seek to unravel the mystery of the Day of Mourning.<br><br>Metrol (ruins)<br><br>Before its fall, Cyre was a melting pot of cultures and races including humans, elves, halflings, and warforged. Now, the remnants of its populace are scattered, often warped by the magical devastation.<br><br>The Mournland is filled with horrors such as living spells, warforged titans, and mutated beasts. The dead do not rest easy here, and necromantic energies give rise to undead abominations.]]></description><link>session-1\regions\mournland-(formerly-cyre).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session -1/Regions/Mournland (formerly Cyre).md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:46:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Regions]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The material plane of Eberron is made up of six continents surrounded by oceans and a vast underworld.<br>
<br>Aerenal
<br>Argonnessen
<br>Everice
<br>Khorvaire
<br>Sarlona
<br>Xen'drik
<br>Khyber - Underdark. Eberron underworld existing beneath the continents and oceans.
<br>Adventure primarily takes place in the central region of Khorvaire known as the Five Nations.<br>
<br>Aundair (Scholarly)
<br>Breland (Cosmopolitan)
<br>Karrnath (Militaristic)
<br>Thrane (Theocratic)
<br>Mournland (Formerly Cyre, but now an uninhabited haunted zone.)
]]></description><link>session-1\regions\regions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session -1/Regions/Regions.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:46:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thrane]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Religious quests, crusades, holy wars.<br><br>Thrane is a theocracy ruled by the Church of the Silver Flame, where faith and zealotry are the order of the day. Think of The Crusades meets The Witcher, where holy warriors battle against fiendish threats and religious fervor shapes every action. Adventurers might join the church in its holy crusades, defend against demonic incursions, or navigate the political intricacies of a nation ruled by faith. This is a land where divine light battles against encroaching darkness.<br><br>Flamekeep<br><br>Thrane's population is primarily human, with some dwarves and halflings. The Church of the Silver Flame unites the people in their faith, fostering a culture of devotion and zeal.<br><br>Creatures in Thrane often include fiendish monsters, demons, and corrupted beings. The holy warriors of the Silver Flame also deal with undead and other dark threats.]]></description><link>session-1\regions\thrane.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session -1/Regions/Thrane.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:45:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Session -1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
tete
<br>]]></description><link>session-1\session-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session -1/Session -1.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:03:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to Eberron]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Welcome to Eberron, a world where ancient magic pulses through the land, mysteries lie hidden in every shadow, and epic adventures await those brave enough to seek them.<br><br>Our journey begins with some initial planning to shape the kind of game and adventure we want to experience. We'll think about the type of campaign, the dynamics of our adventuring party, and how these elements will blend to create an unforgettable story.<br>To get started, head over to the Session "-1" (Preparation) section to get yourself ready for the adventure ahead.<br><br><br><br><br>To be added<br><br>To be added<br><br>To be added]]></description><link>home.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Home.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 13:53:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>