<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Ebberon]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.ico</url><title>Ebberon</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 02:05:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 02:05:52 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>Aaron Percival</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Aundair]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br>Welcome to Aundair, a land where magic flows as freely as the wine from its vineyards. Picture the charm of Harry Potter's Hogwarts spread across an entire nation. Here, the air is thick with enchantment, from the floating towers of Arcanix to the magical markets of Fairhaven. Adventurers will find themselves unraveling arcane mysteries, engaging in wizard duels, and navigating the sophisticated intrigues of high society. This is a place where knowledge is power, and the arcane arts hold sway over all.<br><br>Fairhaven<br><br>Aundair is home to a diverse population including humans, half-elves, elves, gnomes, and changelings. The people of Aundair are known for their intelligence, charisma, and magical prowess.<br><br>The creatures found in Aundair range from domesticated magical beasts and constructs to wild fey creatures in the untamed forests. Arcane experiments occasionally give rise to magical anomalies and rogue elementals.]]></description><link>session-1\regions\aundair.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session -1/Regions/Aundair.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 01:52:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Breland]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br>Breland is a land of contrasts, where the sprawling countryside meets the towering cityscape of Sharn. Imagine a world that blends the neon-lit hustle of Cyberpunk 2077 with the noir mystery of The Wolf Among Us. In Sharn, the City of Towers, adventurers can lose themselves in the labyrinthine streets, unravel dark conspiracies in the shadowy undercity, or climb the social ladder amidst the glittering spires. This is a place where urban adventures abound, and every corner turned might reveal a new ally or a deadly foe.<br><br>Wroat<br><br>Breland boasts a rich tapestry of races including humans, halflings, dwarves, gnomes, and warforged. The cosmopolitan nature of Sharn attracts individuals from all across Khorvaire.<br><br>In Breland, you might encounter various urban creatures such as rat swarms and street thugs, as well as magical beings like gargoyles and invisible stalkers. The rural areas are home to more traditional threats like bandits and wild beasts.]]></description><link>session-1\regions\breland.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session -1/Regions/Breland.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 01:52:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cyre (Mournland)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br>Once the heart of innovation and culture, Cyre is now a land of eerie silence and haunting beauty, known as the Mournland. Imagine the oppressive atmosphere of Dark Souls, where every step into the mist could uncover a lost relic or a twisted monstrosity. The ruins of Metrol and other cities lie in wait, holding the secrets of the cataclysm that turned Cyre into a barren wasteland. Adventurers will face mutated creatures, navigate deadly magical anomalies, and seek to unravel the mystery of the Day of Mourning.<br><br>Metrol<br><br>Before its fall, Cyre was a melting pot of cultures and races including humans, elves, halflings, and warforged. Now, the remnants of its populace are scattered, often warped by the magical devastation.<br><br>The Mournland is filled with horrors such as living spells, warforged titans, and mutated beasts. The dead do not rest easy here, and necromantic energies give rise to undead abominations.]]></description><link>session-1\regions\cyre-(mournland).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session -1/Regions/Cyre (Mournland).md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 01:54:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to Eberron]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Welcome to Eberron, a world where magic and adventure abound.]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 01:42:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>