<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Ebberon]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.ico</url><title>Ebberon</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 12:01:59 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 12:01:57 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>Aaron Percival</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[0. Rules and Expectations]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>We come together to have fun and share a great adventure.
<br>Treat everyone with respect and kindness.
<br>Be considerate of each other's feelings and perspectives.
<br>Communicate openly with the DM and fellow players.
<br>If you have any concerns or ideas, please share them—constructive feedback helps improve the game for everyone.
<br><br>
<br>We aim to create a safe and inclusive environment for all participants.
<br>If any content or situation makes you uncomfortable, let the group or the DM know immediately.
<br>We'll make adjustments to ensure everyone feels comfortable and included.
<br><br>
<br>Our sessions are scheduled at specific times.
<br>Please be punctual and ready to play at the agreed-upon time.
<br>If you can't make it to a session, inform the group in advance.
<br><br>
<br>Pay attention and stay engaged in the game.
<br>Avoid distractions like mobile phones or side conversations during the session.
<br>Immerse yourself in the story and contribute actively to the adventure.
<br><br>
<br>Remember to separate your knowledge as a player from your character's knowledge.
<br>Let your character discover information organically within the game world.
<br>This maintains the integrity and excitement of the story.
<br><br>
<br>Familiarize yourself with the basic rules of Dungeons &amp; Dragons.
<br>D&amp;D is a collaborative storytelling experience; the goal is collective enjoyment rather than winning.
<br>Play fair and respect the DM's rulings.
<br>Don't hesitate to ask questions if you're unsure about something—it's okay to learn as you go.
<br><br>
<br>Bring creativity to your character and actions.
<br>Think outside the box and contribute to the narrative.
<br>Your imagination is a key part of what makes the game exciting and memorable.
<br><br>
<br>If conflicts arise, whether in-character or out-of-character, address them calmly and respectfully.
<br>In-character conflicts can add depth to the story but should not affect real-life relationships among players.
<br>The DM is there to help mediate and resolve issues.
<br>Keep the focus on having a positive and enjoyable experience for everyone.
<br><br>
<br>Character Development: Invest time in developing your character's backstory and motivations. This enriches the game for everyone.
<br>Session Readiness: Ensure you have all necessary materials ready before the session starts, including updated character sheets and any personal notes.
<br><br>
<br>Respect the game world and the narrative crafted by the DM.
<br>Make decisions that align with your character's personality and background.
<br>Help build a cohesive and immersive story by engaging with the setting and other characters.
<br>DM Question
<br>Does anyone have questions or need clarification on any of the ground rules?
<br>Are there any additional ground rules you think we should include?
<br>Is everyone comfortable with the expectations we've set for the game?
<br><br><br>DM QuestionHow long can the group reasonably commit to playing?<br>
Options: Specific number of weeks, months, or years.<br><br>DM QuestionHow often would the group like to play?<br>
Options: Once a week, twice a month, monthly, etc.<br><br>DM QuestionWhich days and times work best for everyone?<br>
Please discuss your availability and time zone considerations.<br><br>DM QuestionWhere shall we play our sessions? Decide on a primary location (physical venue or online platform) and a backup option.<br><br>DM QuestionWhere shall we play our sessions?<br>
Decide on a primary location and a backup option.<br><br>DM QuestionHow long should we wait if someone is late before starting the session?<br>
Options: Number of minutes to wait, or start on time regardless.<br><br>DM QuestionHow should we communicate if we're going to be late or absent?<br>
Agree on a preferred method (e.g., group chat, text message) and any advance notice required.<br><br>DM Discussion PointUnder what circumstances should a session be canceled or rescheduled?<br>
Discuss criteria such as the number of absent players, emergencies, or scheduling conflicts.<br><br>DM QuestionIf a player is absent, what should happen to their character?
Options:

<br>Be played by the DM.
<br>Be played by another player.
<br>Remain with the party but stay inactive.
<br>Be absent from the party for that session.
<br>Be controlled collectively by the group.
<br><br><br><br><br><br>Dice, laptop/other way to access the VTT<br><br><br>DM QuestionHow should we determine character ability scores?
Options:

<br>Standard Array
<br>Point Buy System
<br>Rolling Dice
<br>Player's Choice
<br><br>DM RuleYou may select any playable species from:

<br>The 2024 Player's Handbook

AND

<br>Any official Eberron sourcebooks, including::


<br>Eberron: Rising From the Last War (2019, WotC)
<br>Exploring Eberron (2020, Dungeon Masters Guild)
<br>Chronicles of Eberron (2022, Dungeon Masters Guild)
<br>Frontiers of Eberron: Quickstone (2024, Dungeon Masters Guild)
<br>DM RuleAll classes from the 2024 Player's Handbook are available for this campaign. Classes found in other source material including Eberron sourcebooks are not available to play.<br><br>DM RuleFor this campaign, you have two options:

<br>Pick a background from the PHB (Player's Handbook).
<br>Create a custom background using the format below.
<br><br>DM RuleDO NOT select any starting equipment. You will have gold from both your class and your background. Record this on your player sheet for now.
You MAY select a starting trinket.<br><br>DM RuleYour characters are NOT dragonmarked<br><br>DM RuleCharacters with an evil alignment are not allowed in this campaign.
Your character must be able to cooperate with the group and have motivations that fit the overall tone of the story. Consider creating a character who can work with others, even if they have different perspectives or goals.<br><br><br>DM DesireUse Exerience Points (XP)<br><br>DM QuestionHow should hit points be increased upon leveling up?
Options:

<br>Roll
<br>Fixed by Class
<br><br>DM QuestionHow should dice rolling be done?
Options:

<br>Real dice
<br>Digital
<br>Choice
<br><br>DM QuestionHow should initiative rolling be done?
Options:

<br>Players roll individually
<br>DM Roll all in VTT
<br><br>DM QuestionHow strictly should we track encumbrance and inventory?
Options:

<br>Use standard encumbrance rules
<br>Use simplified rules
<br>Not track encumbrance
<br>DM Magaic
<br><br>Death is a significant aspect of the game that can greatly impact the story and player experience. It's important to find a balance between understanding the risks and consequences of death and ensuring that players don't take excessive risks due to a lack of meaningful repercussions.<br>Some considerations include:<br>
<br>Let-the-Dice-Fall-Where-They-May: Embrace the risk of combat where, if an enemy lands a critical hit, characters might die—even in the first session. This approach underscores the seriousness of dangerous situations and encourages careful decision-making.    
<br>Unconsciousness at Zero Hit Points: Dropping to zero hit points renders a character unconscious but not immediately dead, allowing for recovery as long as someone survives. This reduces sudden character deaths while still highlighting the peril of combat.    
<br>Flexible Resurrection Rules: Make resurrection more accessible by adjusting requirements (e.g., the cleric doesn't need diamonds for revivify as long as they have the equivalent gold). This can ease the finality of death but may lessen the perceived risks if resurrection is too easy.    
<br>Lasting Scars or Injuries: Instead of death, a character who drops to zero hit points survives with a lasting scar or injury, adding depth to their story. This provides consequences without removing the character from the game, balancing risk and continuity.    
<br>Balancing Risk and Reward: Ensure that death has meaningful consequences to encourage thoughtful play. If consequences are too severe, players may become overly cautious; if too light, they may act recklessly.
<br>DM QuestionHow should we handle character death and resurrection to balance the risks and consequences in our game?
Considerations:

<br>Maintaining meaningful consequences for risky actions.
<br>Avoiding overly harsh penalties that discourage engagement.
<br>Preventing reckless behavior due to negligible consequences.
<br>Keeping the game fun and the story impactful.

Options:

<br>Use standard rules: death saving throws and resurrection spells as written.
<br>Characters become unconscious at zero hit points, with death occurring under specific conditions.
<br>Allow for easier resurrection but introduce costs or side effects to maintain stakes.
<br>Implement lasting scars or injuries as consequences of dropping to zero hit points.
<br><br><br>DM QuestionIs food and drink welcome at the table during sessions? Is alcohol?<br><br>DM QuestionWhat are our expectations regarding smartphones and electronic devices at the table?
Options:

<br>Allowed for game-related use only.
<br>Permitted freely.
<br>Minimized to avoid distractions.
<br>Turned off or silenced during sessions.
<br><br>DM QuestionHow much time should we spend checking rules during the game?
Options:

<br>All rules must be followed so time is no option!
<br>Limit to a few minutes per instance.
<br>Make a best guess and check after the session.
<br><br>DM QuestionWhat style of role-playing does the group prefer?
Options:

<br>In-depth role-playing like Critical Role.
<br>Casual and light-hearted like Stranger Things.
<br>A mix of both, depending on the situation.
<br><br><br>As your DM, I prioritize storytelling and narrative flow. The rules of Dungeons &amp; Dragons serve as a framework, but I may choose to ignore or override a rule in a particular scene to enhance the story or maintain pacing.<br>
<br>Rules as Guidelines: While I respect the rules, I may make on-the-spot decisions to keep the game moving smoothly.
<br>Open to Input: If you notice a rule that might have been overlooked, please bring it to my attention. Often, it may be an oversight.
<br>Final Decisions: If I acknowledge a rule and decide to intentionally ignore it for narrative reasons, I'd appreciate if we can proceed without further debate during the session.
<br>DM QuestionAre you comfortable with a story-driven approach where rules might be adjusted for narrative purposes?<br><br>While storytelling is a priority, the rules are still important for fairness and consistency.<br>
<br>Rule Discussions: If there's a disagreement about a rule, we can briefly discuss it, but I may make a final decision to keep the game moving.
<br>Post-Session Clarifications: For complex rule questions, we can delve deeper after the session to find a solution that works for everyone.
<br>DM QuestionAre you agreeable to addressing detailed rule discussions after the session to maintain game flow?<br><br>I enjoy involving players in the creation of the game's narrative and world details.<br>DM DesirePlayers take a proactive approach to help advancing plot element.<br>
<br>
Player Contributions: I may ask you to add details to a scene or describe elements that your character notices.<br>
Example: “There's a mob of zombies—they're rotting villagers! Describe one of the zombies that draws your attention.”

<br>
Enhancing Engagement: This approach helps give you a concrete investment in the scene and enriches the story with ideas I might not have considered.    

<br>
Option to Pass: If you're not comfortable or prefer not to be put on the spot, you can always say "Pass."

<br>DM QuestionAre you comfortable contributing to scene descriptions and participating in collaborative storytelling?<br><br>Dungeons &amp; Dragons gameplay is often divided among three main pillars: Exploration, Social Interaction, and Combat. Understanding your preferences helps me tailor the campaign to ensure everyone is engaged and enjoying the game.<br>
<br>Exploration: Discovering new places, solving puzzles, and overcoming environmental challenges.
<br>Social Interaction: Engaging with NPCs, negotiating, and role-playing conversations.
<br>Combat: Tactical battles, strategy, and action-packed encounters.
<br>DM QuestionWhat is your preferred balance among the three pillars of gameplay: Exploration, Social Interaction, and Combat?
Options:

<br>A balanced mix of all three.
<br>More focus on [Exploration/Social Interaction/Combat].
<br>Less emphasis on [Exploration/Social Interaction/Combat].
<br>Flexible, open to any balance as long as the story is engaging.
<br><br>Lines and Veils are tools used to establish boundaries within our game to ensure that all players feel comfortable and safe. They help define which topics are acceptable, which should be approached with discretion, and which should be avoided entirely.<br>
<br>
Lines are hard boundaries—subjects that players do not want to be included in the game under any circumstances. These topics should not be brought up at all, even in passing.

<br>
Veils are softer boundaries—subjects that can be part of the story but are kept in soft focus or occur off-camera. These elements might be mentioned or implied but are not described in detail. 

<br>It's the difference between "this doesn't come up at all" and "this may be a part of the plot but treated with some discretion."<br>Understanding each other's Lines and Veils allows us to create a respectful and enjoyable gaming experience for everyone. It's important to discuss these boundaries openly and honestly.<br><br>
<br>
Line Example: A player may state, "I don't want cruelty to animals to feature in this game at all, even as a scene-setting detail." This means the DM and other players should avoid introducing this element entirely.

<br>
Veil Example: A player may state, "I'd be OK with someone mentioning a horse looking overworked or a dog looking neglected and hungry to show how bad things are but I don't want a scene of the villain kicking puppies specifically." This means the DM and other players be careful with how they approach the topic.

<br>Even after setting initial Lines and Veils, it's crucial to remain open to further discussions. Sometimes, you might not realize a topic is uncomfortable until it arises during gameplay.<br>DM Questions
<br>Are there any topics or themes that are Lines for you - subjects you do not want included in the game at all?
<br>Are there any topics or themes that are Veils for you — subjects you're okay with as long as they are handled discreetly?
<br>What is your preferred way of addressing new boundaries that might arise during gameplay?
]]></description><link>dm\sessions\session-0\0.-rules-and-expectations.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">DM/Sessions/Session 0/0. Rules and Expectations.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 18:22:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[1. Welcome to Eberron]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Cover Art1.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-cover-art1.png"><br>Welcome to Eberron, a world of magic woven into the fabric of daily life where airships soar between towered cities, lightning rails race across continents, and elemental power fuels industry and innovation. But this is also a land scarred by a century of war, where fragile truces barely hold the nations together, and shadows of the Last War loom large. Intrigue, danger, and moral ambiguity define the world, where dragonmarked dynasties hold power rivaling nations, and nothing is ever as simple as it seems. This is a place where adventure awaits, and your choices will shape the future.<br>Let's explore what makes Eberron a unique setting for our adventure<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Magic Everywhere.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-magic-everywhere.png"><br>In Eberron, magic isn't something reserved for mysterious wizards or rare moments of wonder. No, here magic powers the world itself. Picture this: vast cities where the streets are lit not by mundane flames, but by everbright lanterns—arcane lights that never flicker, never fade. Look up, and you’ll see airships drifting lazily between towers that scrape the sky, their bound elementals crackling with energy. Beneath your feet, lightning rails zip across the continent, powered by elemental forces as passengers travel at speeds undreamed of elsewhere. This is Eberron—where magic isn’t just something you study, it’s something you live with every day.<br>But this isn’t your typical fantasy magic—it’s an integral part of life, almost like technology in our world. Magewrights, specialists in small but essential spells, use magic to craft fine items, maintain city infrastructure, and even breed magical animals. In the forges of House Cannith, ancient magic is combined with ingenuity to produce wonders like the warforged—living constructs made of wood and steel, given life and sentience to serve as soldiers during the Last War.<br>In Eberron, magic shapes everything. It builds the cities, fuels the economy, and created beings like the warforged, who are still searching for their place in a world that once needed them for destruction but now must find a way to live with them in peace. Magic, in Eberron, is both a tool for progress and a force of disruption. It’s everywhere, in everything, and it’s waiting for you to tap into its wonders—or its dangers.<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Twist.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-twist.png"><br>In Eberron, nothing is quite as it seems. Here, the lines between good and evil blur, and the world is steeped in moral ambiguity. Imagine a place where the most noble hero might be forced to make dark, questionable decisions, and even the brightest lights cast the deepest shadows. This is a world of intrigue and noir, where corruption festers beneath the surface and powerful organizations pull the strings behind the scenes. In Eberron, good and evil aren’t just black and white—they’re shaped by culture, circumstance, and personal ambition.<br>One of the most striking differences in Eberron is that traditional alignments don’t always apply in the way you might expect. That gold dragon you meet? It may not be the benevolent sage you're used to. It could have its own selfish or even destructive agenda. The orc you encounter might be a paragon of law and virtue, and the drow lurking in the shadows may be no more dangerous than the humans from Aundair. In Eberron, morality is fluid. A person’s actions are not defined by the color of their skin or the shape of their body, but by their choices, their experiences, and their ambitions.<br>That doesn’t mean evil doesn’t exist—it’s everywhere. But the evil you’ll encounter in Eberron isn’t always a cackling villain twirling a mustache. Instead, it might be the kindly innkeeper who shorts her customers to pad her own pocket, or the guard who takes bribes to let criminals through the gate. You might even meet a crusading paladin of the Silver Flame—someone who fights for righteousness—but who crosses lines, like zealously hunting down heretics with no regard for collateral damage.<br>The reality is that evil in Eberron often looks like selfishness, greed, and a willingness to harm others for personal gain. The mage who sacrifices innocents in the name of a cure, the spy who tortures for information—these are people who see their actions as necessary, even righteous. In this world, your decisions may not just be about right and wrong—they may be about what you’re willing to live with, or who you’re willing to trust in a place where trust is a rare and precious thing.<br>So, as you explore Eberron, remember that the classic rules don’t always apply. Fiends might offer genuine help, dragons may pursue their own agendas, and allies could become your greatest enemies. Your choices will carry weight, and the consequences will ripple across the world in ways you never expected. In Eberron, nothing is ever simple—and that’s what makes it so captivating.<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Pulp Adventure.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-pulp-adventure.png"><br>Eberron is a world where high adventure collides with a sense of constant danger. It’s a place where you’ll leap from the deck of an airship as it crashes in flames, chase down enemies on the speeding lightning rail, and battle mad cultists in the shadowy depths of ancient ruins. It’s a world that embraces the excitement and action of pulp fiction—filled with bold heroes, sinister villains, and impossible odds.<br>Imagine the sprawling jungles of Xen'drik, a continent teeming with mysteries from lost civilizations. Here, dark elves ride giant scorpions and hurl metal boomerangs with deadly precision, while deep within, forgotten ruins hide treasures and powers beyond imagining. Or perhaps you find yourself racing across Khorvaire on the lightning rail, your foes closing in as the train rockets toward its destination, suspended above the ground by arcs of elemental energy. And above it all, airships powered by bound elementals sail across the sky—if you’re lucky, you’ll end up fighting on one of these, and if you’re really lucky, you’ll survive.<br>But it’s not just about exotic locations and thrilling action. Eberron is home to mad cultists plotting to unleash the chaos of the Dragon Below, crazy wizards studying the shifting planes as they await the right celestial conjunction to power their infernal machines, and more than a few shadowy organizations all vying for world domination. Everywhere you go, there’s the potential for high-stakes encounters, grand spectacles, and dangerous schemes.<br>At the heart of it all is the Draconic Prophecy—a cosmic puzzle woven into the fabric of the world itself. Dragons, immortals, and fiends all seek to interpret its secrets, believing they can shape the future to their will. But the Prophecy doesn’t predict a single destiny. It shows countless possible futures, all shaped by the choices of mortals like you. Every action, every decision, could shift the balance of power in ways you can’t yet imagine.<br>In Eberron, you’re not just an adventurer—you’re a hero in a world teetering on the edge. Your strength, skill, and courage will be tested at every turn, but so will your wits and your heart. Whether you’re leaping from crashing airships, battling evil cults in forgotten ruins, or outwitting ancient dragons, every moment in Eberron is filled with excitement, danger, and the chance to make your mark on a world where nothing is ever quite what it seems.<br>And remember—remarkable heroes often find themselves up against equally remarkable villains. You’ll face rivals who match your strength, villains who return after seeming death with vengeance on their minds, and shadowy figures whose plans stretch across entire nations. Every victory will push your foes to grow stronger, forcing you to rise to meet the challenge. Welcome to the pulp adventure of Eberron, where the stakes are always high, and the only way out is through.<br><br>In Eberron, true power lies not just in crowns and swords, but in the dragonmarked houses—ancient dynasties whose bloodlines bear magical sigils known as dragonmarks. These marks aren’t tattoos; they’re living magic, granting unique abilities to those lucky enough to manifest them. Imagine heirs with the Mark of Healing, raising the dead for House Jorasco, or airship pilots of House Lyrandar, controlling the skies with the Mark of Storms.<br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Dragonmarks.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-dragonmarks.png"><br>These houses run like powerful corporations, monopolizing industries across Khorvaire. If you need healing, travel, or banking, you’ll deal with one of these houses. Their influence rivals that of entire nations, and their reach is everywhere—from cities to wilderness. Even independent businesses often bear their approval, showing the sheer control they hold over commerce.<br>Dragonmarks appear during adolescence, but not every heir receives one. Those who do gain prestige, adding the 'd’ prefix to their names, becoming part of an elite force that shapes Eberron’s future. Yet the dragonmarked houses are filled with intrigue—some heirs are exiled, called excoriates, while foundlings possess marks without the backing of the powerful families.<br>Once kept in check by the Korth Edicts, the houses’ power has only grown since the Last War. Now, they push the limits of their influence, with some wondering if they’ll ever be stopped. For adventurers like you, the dragonmarked houses offer both opportunity and danger. Aligning with them could bring wealth and power, but crossing them could mean your downfall.<br>The marks and their houses are,<br>
<br>
House Medani (Mark of Detection): Masters of uncovering hidden threats, specializing in risk assessment, protection, and community service over power.

<br>
House Tharashk (Mark of Finding): Experts in tracking, bounty hunting, and dragonshard prospecting, driven by the unified strength of human and half-orc clans.

<br>
House Vadalis (Mark of Handling): Masters of breeding and training animals, from mundane beasts to magical creatures like hippogriffs, with rumors of even more ambitious magebreeding experiments.

<br>
House Jorasco (Mark of Healing): Renowned healers who can cure the sick and even pull souls back from death—at a price—while rumors persist of darker experiments conducted during the Last War.

<br>
House Ghallanda (Mark of Hospitality):&nbsp;Masters of comfort and connection, Ghallanda halflings run inns, taverns, and sanctuaries across the Five Nations, offering both hospitality and quiet influence through a network of bound favors and well-placed allies.

<br>
House Cannith (Mark of Making): Masters of creation, House Cannith controls the manufacture of weapons, warforged, and magical goods, but the house is fractured—three rival barons vie for leadership after the Mourning devastated their ancestral seat in Cyre.

<br>
House Orien (Mark of Passage): Masters of transportation, House Orien controls the lightning rail and overland caravans, but faces growing challenges from the Mournland's destruction and the rise of Lyrandar airships.

<br>
House Sivis (Mark of Scribing): House Sivis, led by gnomes, masters communication—managing speaking stones and training scribes and interpreters. Neutral and discreet, they facilitate long-distance messages and notarize important documents with their arcane marks.

<br>
House Deneith (Mark of Sentinel): House Deneith, born of war, offers elite mercenaries, bodyguards, and law-enforcing Sentinel Marshals. Neutral yet powerful, they serve all sides while guarding their honor and keeping Khorvaire safe from danger.

<br>
The Houses of Shadow (Mark of Shadow): House Phiarlan and House Thuranni excel in illusion and espionage, wielding the Mark of Shadow to deceive, entertain, and assassinate. Though split by a bitter feud, the houses remain unmatched as spies and artists, sculpting secrets from the shadows of Khorvaire.

<br>
House Lyrandar (Mark of Storm): Masters of wind and sea, House Lyrandar uses the Mark of Storm to command weather and elemental vessels, ruling both maritime trade and the skies with their airships, while their island enclave, Stormhome, stands as their sanctuary and seat of power.

<br>
House Kundarak (Mark of Warding): Guardians of wealth and security, House Kundarak wields the Mark of Warding to protect valuables with mystic locks and wards, operating both a vast banking network and the infamous Dreadhold prison, renowned for its legendary security and extradimensional vaults.

<br><br>The Last War may have ended, but its shadow looms large over Eberron. For a century, the Five Nations fought a brutal conflict that shattered the kingdom of Galifar. Though the Treaty of Thronehold declared peace, it’s a fragile one, held together by fear and uncertainty. The Mourning—an inexplicable cataclysm that obliterated Cyre in a single day—serves as a chilling reminder of the devastation that unchecked power can wreak. The land of Cyre is now a twisted wasteland known as the Mournland, a scar on the continent of Khorvaire, haunted by undead and living spells that still roam the battlefield.<br>The atmosphere in Eberron echoes the tensions of post-World War I Europe. Soldiers return home unsure of their place in a world at peace. Nations eye each other with suspicion, their leaders quietly preparing for the inevitable return of conflict. Magic-driven war machines and weapons of incredible power litter the landscape, remnants of a war that never really ended in the hearts and minds of the people.<br>The warforged, living constructs created for battle, now walk free—granted citizenship by the treaty that ended the war. But for many, peace is an uncomfortable fit. Warforged were designed for a world at war, and many struggle to find their place in a society that fears them as tools of destruction with no purpose beyond combat.<br>The Mourning stands at the heart of every conversation about the future. Was it an accident? A weapon gone wrong? Or something far worse, still waiting to be unleashed? Fear of the Mourning keeps the nations in check, but for how long? Everyone knows that peace in Eberron is temporary—the Last War may have paused, but few believe it’s truly over.<br>The world of Eberron is waiting for you—full of mystery, magic, and adventure. What will you make of it?]]></description><link>dm\sessions\session-0\1.-welcome-to-eberron.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">DM/Sessions/Session 0/1. Welcome to Eberron.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 18:23:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\image-eberron-cover-art1.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib\media\image-eberron-cover-art1.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2. Eberron's History]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Creation Myth.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-creation-myth.png"><br>Long before the rise of mortals or the first breath of history, the world of Eberron was shaped by forces as old as existence itself. According to myth, three Progenitor Dragons—Siberys,&nbsp;Eberron, and&nbsp;Khyber—wove the fabric of the planes, bringing the universe into being. Their creation was a perfect balance of light and shadow, order and chaos, life and death. But harmony was fleeting.&nbsp;Khyber, driven by ambition and darkness, betrayed&nbsp;Siberys, striking him down and scattering his golden essence across the sky as the&nbsp;Ring of Siberys. To contain this evil,&nbsp;Eberron&nbsp;coiled herself around&nbsp;Khyber, imprisoning the dark force within her coils and becoming the very world itself—the living, breathing planet you now call home. Thus, the Dragon Above, the Dragon Between, and the Dragon Below define the very essence of Eberron, their legacy etched into the land, sky, and the shadows beneath.<br>Though many cultures consider this story a myth, it resonates across the world, with Siberys embodying the sky and magic, Eberron as the life-giving earth, and Khyber as the dark underworld, filled with aberrations and fiends. The tale of their cosmic struggle remains a foundation of Eberron’s lore, with its influence still felt today in the world’s magic, natural forces, and the terrifying creatures that dwell deep below.<br><br>The rise and fall of great civilizations mark the mortal history of Eberron.<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Age of Demons.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-age-of-demons.png"><br>Over 100,000 years ago, Eberron was ruled by the dark children of Khyber—fiends, aberrations, and monsters that rose from the depths. Among them were the Overlords, thirty immortal archfiends who shaped the world to their malevolent desires. For millennia, these fiends reigned supreme, bending reality itself to their will. No civilization could stand against them.<br>But the tide of this dark era shifted when the Sovereign Host, along with an alliance of dragons and the celestial couatl, rose to challenge the overlords. The war that followed saw untold sacrifice, with the couatl binding the archfiends into eternal prisons using their own life force, creating the Silver Flame, a power that endures to this day. Though the overlords are bound, their influence still lingers, and those who seek to free them—like the Lords of Dust—work in the shadows, ensuring that the struggle against these ancient evils never truly ends.<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Age of Giants.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-age-of-giants.png"><br>Around 80,000 years ago, the giants of Xen'drik rose to power, unlocking secrets of arcane magic that still surpass modern understanding. In their prime, these giant civilizations achieved incredible feats, binding elementals and creating eldritch machines of immense power. But their reach extended too far. When a war broke out between the giants and the quori of Dal Quor, the giants ended the conflict by destroying one of Eberron's moons, severing Dal Quor's link to the world.<br>This victory came at a terrible cost. Uprisings followed, most notably by the elves, who had long been enslaved by the giants. As the giants prepared to unleash catastrophic magic to crush the rebellion, the dragons intervened, emerging from Argonnessen to shatter the once-great civilizations of Xen'drik. They laid powerful curses upon the land, ensuring that no great empire could ever rise again. These draconic curses—such as the Traveler's Curse and Du’rashka Tul—warp space, twist minds, and keep Xen'drik a land of perilous, ever-shifting wilderness.<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Age of Monsters.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-age-of-monsters.png"><br>The Age of Monsters was dominated by the rise and fall of mighty civilizations on Khorvaire, especially the goblinoid Empire of Dhakaan, which flourished for over ten thousand years. From around 16,000 years ago, Dhakaan spread across central Khorvaire, pushing other races—dwarves, dragonborn, and orcs—to the continent's margins. But it wasn’t the only power shaping the land. After fleeing the destruction of Xen'drik, elves settled on Aerenal, around 25,000 years ago, forming the mystical Undying Court and the warrior tradition of the Tairnadal.<br>The Dhakaani Empire faced its greatest challenge around 9,000 years ago, with the invasion of the daelkyr, who led armies of aberrations from the plane of Xoriat. Though the Gatekeeper druids and Dhakaani champions ultimately sealed the daelkyr in Khyber, the damage was done. Madness crept through the goblinoid ranks, eroding the unity of their civilization. By 5,000 years ago, the empire crumbled into ruin and civil war, leaving behind scattered remnants of their once-great culture.<br>Today, Dhakaani ruins lie beneath many modern cities, and adventurers often explore these forgotten halls. The daelkyr’s influence persists as well, manifesting in the Cults of the Dragon Below and the Gatekeeper druids who continue to guard against aberrant threats. This ancient history still shapes the present, as goblins and orcs in places like Darguun seek to reclaim the glory of their fallen empire, while dwarves in the Mror Holds unearth strange relics from the lost Realm Below.<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Age of Humanity.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-age-of-humanity.png"><br>In the wake of the Age of Monsters, a new era began across Khorvaire—one that saw the rise of humanity and the discovery of the first dragonmarks. Scholars debate whether this era should be called the Age of Humanity or the Dragonmarked Age, as both human civilizations and the dragonmarked houses came into power. This era saw humanity spread from Sarlona to Khorvaire, where they established powerful city-states. During this time, the foundation for the Five Nations was laid, marking the early history of Galifar and the dominance of humans over the continent.<br><br>Key events include the arrival of human settlers led by the adventurer Lhazaar, who established the Lhazaar Principalities around 3,000 years ago. Simultaneously, the first dragonmarks began to manifest, including the Mark of Hospitality among the halflings of the Talenta Plains and the Mark of Death among the elves of Aerenal. The elves soon faced tragedy as the Undying Court and dragons from Argonnessen annihilated the House of Vol, bearers of the Mark of Death, due to their dangerous experiments in combining elven and draconic magic.<br>By 2,500 years ago, human city-states like Korth, Metrol, and Wroat had risen to prominence, marking the early stages of what would become the Five Nations of Galifar. The discovery of dragonmarks continued, with the Mark of Making appearing in Metrol, and the Mark of Warding among the dwarves of the Ironroot Mountains. Giants and goblinoid civilizations receded further, their power diminished by human expansion. This growth led to conflicts, such as Karrn the Conqueror's failed attempts to unify Khorvaire under Karrnath, establishing centuries-long power struggles.<br>This time also saw the emergence of new races, including the kalashtar in Adar, formed by monks who voluntarily bound their spirits to the quori, creating a powerful new lineage. New cultures, such as the Venomous Demesne in modern Droaam, emerged from refugee tiefling and human settlements escaping Sarlona’s upheavals.<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - War of the Mark.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-war-of-the-mark.png"><br>The War of the Mark was a dark chapter in Eberron’s history, marking the near-extinction of those with aberrant dragonmarks—strange and dangerous powers feared by the populace. Around 1,500 years ago, when the dragonmarked houses joined together as the Twelve, they turned their influence against those with aberrant marks. Propaganda stoked fear, casting the aberrant-marked as uncontrollable threats to society. Though many were innocent, they became scapegoats in a purge led by House Deneith soldiers, Vadalis trackers, and Medani inquisitors.<br>The war culminated in the rise of powerful champions like Halas Tarkanan and the Lady of the Plague, who made their final stand in Sharn, declaring it a haven for the persecuted. When defeat became inevitable, Tarkanan used his mark to shatter the city's towers, while the Lady unleashed diseases and vermin, destroying both the city and their enemies. Sharn lay in ruins for centuries afterward, a testament to the war’s devastation.<br>Though the aberrant marks were nearly eradicated, fear and prejudice endured. In recent years, aberrant marks have begun to reappear with growing frequency and power, raising concerns of another purge. Today, the secretive House Tarkanan trains those with aberrant marks, preparing for the possibility of a renewed conflict with the Twelve.<br><br><img alt="Eberron - Image - Galifar.png" src="lib\media\eberron-image-galifar.png"><br>The Kingdom of Galifar stands as a golden age in the history of Khorvaire, an era of peace, progress, and unity. Founded in 1 YK by Galifar Wynarn, the kingdom unified the Five Nations not only through military might but also through diplomacy and a vision of a better world. Under Galifar’s rule, slavery was abolished, justice was reformed, and public education flourished, paving the way for the rise of the merchant class and economic stability. The Arcane Congress, Rekkenmark Academy, and other key institutions were established to serve the common good, fostering an age of advancement.<br>However, Galifar's reign wasn't without flaws. His policy of allowing the dragonmarked houses to dominate certain industries planted the seeds of their immense modern power, leading to near-monopolies that the Korth Edicts only partially curtailed. Additionally, his precarious system of succession—where his children ruled as governors of the Five Nations—sowed the seeds of discord. While this kept the realm stable for nearly nine centuries, it led to numerous rebellions and secessions over the kingdom's history, culminating in the Last War.<br>Despite its eventual downfall in 894 YK, the legacy of Galifar endures. The common laws, institutions, and cultural norms shared across the Five Nations are all remnants of that united past. Even after a century of brutal conflict, many still yearn for the golden age of Galifar and believe that true peace and unity can only be achieved by restoring the kingdom.<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - The Silver Crusade.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-the-silver-crusade.png"><br>The Silver Crusade began as a response to a rising tide of lycanthropy that threatened the western regions of Aundair. Once considered a rare and fearful legend, lycanthropy suddenly grew more virulent and dangerous during the early ninth century, with werewolf attacks and wererat infestations spreading fear and chaos. By 832 YK, the Keeper of the Flame, Jolan Sol, declared lycanthropy a corrupting force that needed to be eradicated, leading the Church of the Silver Flame to launch a brutal fifty-year campaign against the lycanthropes. The first two decades were particularly bloody as templars fought a losing battle against growing hordes of lycanthropes, many of whom were thought to be driven by the influence of a near-freed overlord. However, through decades of conflict, the templars eventually broke the power of the curse, weakening lycanthropy across Khorvaire.<br>Though the templars succeeded in weakening the lycanthropic threat, the Silver Crusade did not end without controversy. The final thirty years saw an ongoing inquisition led by a zealous sect known as the Pure Flame. They sought to purge every last lycanthrope but also targeted innocent shifters and other suspected werecreatures. The Pure Flame's actions created lasting rifts between the followers of the Silver Flame and the shifter communities, particularly in the Eldeen Reaches. While the Silver Crusade began as an effort to protect the people, it ended as a dark chapter of paranoia and hatred.<br>The Crusade's aftermath left a lasting mark on Eberron, with lycanthropy now treated as a serious public health risk. Templars of the Silver Flame are still charged with dealing with lycanthropes, though they often seek to cure rather than kill, except when necessary. Meanwhile, lycanthropes have found havens in places like Droaam and Stormreach, and the scars of the crusade still affect shifters across the continent.<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - The Last War1.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-the-last-war1.png"><br>The Last War was a century-long conflict that shattered the once-united kingdom of Galifar and forever altered the landscape of Khorvaire. After the death of King Jarot in 894 YK, a bitter struggle for succession erupted between his children, plunging the Five Nations into open war. What began as a civil war soon spiraled into a vast and brutal conflict, marked by shifting alliances, political intrigue, and grueling battles. Magic and military innovation fueled the war, giving rise to devastating new weapons and war machines, such as the warforged, constructs created to serve as soldiers in the endless conflict.<br>The war reached its darkest moment on 20 Olarune 994 YK with the Day of Mourning, when the nation of Cyre was obliterated by a mysterious magical cataclysm. The Mourning left behind the Mournland, a twisted wasteland filled with living spells and undead horrors, and claimed over a million lives in a single day. The shock of the Mourning forced the warring nations to the negotiating table, and the conflict came to a fragile end with the signing of the Treaty of Thronehold in 996 YK. Although the war is over, no one claims victory, and many believe that it is only a matter of time before hostilities reignite.<br><br><img alt="Image - Eberron - Mournland Wall.png" src="lib\media\image-eberron-mournland-wall.png"><br>Though the Treaty of Thronehold brought a formal end to the Last War, Khorvaire remains a continent on edge. The scars of the war are everywhere—cities lie in ruins, forests and farmlands are scorched, and refugees from Cyre wander the land, homeless and destitute. The Mourning haunts the continent, with many fearing that its destructive power could return or be harnessed as a weapon. This fear keeps the fragile peace in place, but few believe that it will last.<br>Nations continue to jockey for position, eyeing their neighbors with suspicion while secretly rebuilding their military forces. The rise of new powers, such as the Valenar elves and the goblins of Darguun, further complicates the political landscape. Meanwhile, the dragonmarked houses, having profited enormously during the war, now wield unprecedented power, controlling vital industries such as transportation, banking, and healing. The warforged, once mere tools of war, now walk free, struggling to find their place in a world that once needed them only for battle.<br>As of 998 YK, two years after the war's end, the continent stands at a crossroads. Peace is fragile, and every nation is making preparations for the possibility of future conflict. The mystery of the Mourning looms large, and while some seek to understand its origins, others prepare for its potential return. The Last War may be over, but its shadow lingers across Eberron, and the wounds of the past are far from healed.]]></description><link>dm\sessions\session-0\2.-eberron's-history.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">DM/Sessions/Session 0/2. Eberron's History.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 18:51:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\image-eberron-creation-myth.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib\media\image-eberron-creation-myth.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[3. Eberron's Places]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><img alt="Map - Eberron.png" src="lib\media\map-eberron.png"><br><a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://eberronmap.johnarcadian.com/" target="_blank">https://eberronmap.johnarcadian.com/</a><br>The world of Eberron is vast, diverse, and full of wonders, spanning multiple continents, each with its own distinct cultures, peoples, and dangers.<br>
<br>Khorvaire:  The starting stage of adventures is Khorvaire, the largest and most populous continent. It is a land rich in history, industry, and intrigue—home to towering cities, ancient ruins, and the scars of war. Khorvaire is the heart of the Five Nations, and it is where the Last War unfolded, reshaping the continent forever. Once the unified Kingdom of Galifar, this continent is now a fractured land of independent nations. From the sprawling metropolis of Sharn, the City of Towers, to the icy plains of Karrnath, the lightning rail routes of Breland, and the magical academies of Aundair, Khorvaire is the center of politics, trade, and conflict in Eberron. 
<br>Xen'drik: Southwest of Khorvaire lies Xen'drik, a vast jungle continent filled with ancient ruins and the remnants of the once-great giant civilizations. This land is shrouded in mystery and danger. Adventurers come here seeking treasure, lost magic, and the hidden secrets of the giant empire, but they must contend with the wild, unpredictable magic of the land, and the deadly creatures that call Xen'drik home.
<br>Aerenal: South of Khorvaire lies Aerenal, an island continent ruled by the immortal elves. Here, the elves worship their undying ancestors, who guide their society from beyond death. The island is steeped in ancient magic, with the elves guarding the arcane secrets they’ve accumulated over millennia. Aerenal remains isolated from much of the world, its people focused inward, guarding their ancient rites and secrets.
<br>Argonnessen: Far to the southeast, Argonnessen is the land of dragons, a place forbidden to most mortals. Here, dragons dwell in ancient cities, studying the Draconic Prophecy and guarding secrets that could reshape the world. Few who travel to Argonnessen ever return, and those who do are often forever changed by what they’ve seen.
<br>Sarlona: Across the eastern sea lies the continent of Sarlona, the original birthplace of humanity. Though once home to a multitude of kingdoms, today, the continent is largely dominated by the Inspired—psionic rulers of the Riedran Empire, who command armies of psychic warriors and enforce strict control over their people. Beneath the surface, the Kalashtar—a race of psionically gifted humans bound to spiritual entities called quori—quietly wage a resistance against the Inspired.
<br>Let's take a deeper look at when we'll be starting<br><br><img class="leaflet-image-layer leaflet-zoom-animated" src="lib\media\map-khorvaire.webp" alt="" style="z-index: 1; transform: translate3d(-148px, -412px, 0px); width: 2656px; height: 1673px;"><a class="leaflet-control-zoom-in" href="about:blank#" title="Zoom in" role="button" aria-label="Zoom in">+</a><a class="leaflet-control-zoom-out" href="about:blank#" title="Zoom out" role="button" aria-label="Zoom out">−</a><a class="leaflet-control-fullscreen-button leaflet-bar-part" href="about:blank#" title="View Fullscreen" aria-label="Toggle Full Screen"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="expand" class="svg-inline--fa fa-expand fa-w-14" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M0 180V56c0-13.3 10.7-24 24-24h124c6.6 0 12 5.4 12 12v40c0 6.6-5.4 12-12 12H64v84c0 6.6-5.4 12-12 12H12c-6.6 0-12-5.4-12-12zM288 44v40c0 6.6 5.4 12 12 12h84v84c0 6.6 5.4 12 12 12h40c6.6 0 12-5.4 12-12V56c0-13.3-10.7-24-24-24H300c-6.6 0-12 5.4-12 12zm148 276h-40c-6.6 0-12 5.4-12 12v84h-84c-6.6 0-12 5.4-12 12v40c0 6.6 5.4 12 12 12h124c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24V332c0-6.6-5.4-12-12-12zM160 468v-40c0-6.6-5.4-12-12-12H64v-84c0-6.6-5.4-12-12-12H12c-6.6 0-12 5.4-12 12v124c0 13.3 10.7 24 24 24h124c6.6 0 12-5.4 12-12z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-zoom-markers-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Show All Markers"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="map-marked-alt" class="svg-inline--fa fa-map-marked-alt fa-w-18" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M288 0c-69.59 0-126 56.41-126 126 0 56.26 82.35 158.8 113.9 196.02 6.39 7.54 17.82 7.54 24.2 0C331.65 284.8 414 182.26 414 126 414 56.41 357.59 0 288 0zm0 168c-23.2 0-42-18.8-42-42s18.8-42 42-42 42 18.8 42 42-18.8 42-42 42zM20.12 215.95A32.006 32.006 0 0 0 0 245.66v250.32c0 11.32 11.43 19.06 21.94 14.86L160 448V214.92c-8.84-15.98-16.07-31.54-21.25-46.42L20.12 215.95zM288 359.67c-14.07 0-27.38-6.18-36.51-16.96-19.66-23.2-40.57-49.62-59.49-76.72v182l192 64V266c-18.92 27.09-39.82 53.52-59.49 76.72-9.13 10.77-22.44 16.95-36.51 16.95zm266.06-198.51L416 224v288l139.88-55.95A31.996 31.996 0 0 0 576 426.34V176.02c0-11.32-11.43-19.06-21.94-14.86z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-reset-zoom-icon" href="about:blank#"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="bullseye" class="svg-inline--fa fa-bullseye fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 496 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M248 8C111.03 8 0 119.03 0 256s111.03 248 248 248 248-111.03 248-248S384.97 8 248 8zm0 432c-101.69 0-184-82.29-184-184 0-101.69 82.29-184 184-184 101.69 0 184 82.29 184 184 0 101.69-82.29 184-184 184zm0-312c-70.69 0-128 57.31-128 128s57.31 128 128 128 128-57.31 128-128-57.31-128-128-128zm0 192c-35.29 0-64-28.71-64-64s28.71-64 64-64 64 28.71 64 64-28.71 64-64 64z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-expandable-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Filter Markers" data-draggable="false"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="filter" class="svg-inline--fa fa-filter fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M487.976 0H24.028C2.71 0-8.047 25.866 7.058 40.971L192 225.941V432c0 7.831 3.821 15.17 10.237 19.662l80 55.98C298.02 518.69 320 507.493 320 487.98V225.941l184.947-184.97C520.021 25.896 509.338 0 487.976 0z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-lock-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Unlock Map"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="lock" class="svg-inline--fa fa-lock fa-w-14" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M400 224h-24v-72C376 68.2 307.8 0 224 0S72 68.2 72 152v72H48c-26.5 0-48 21.5-48 48v192c0 26.5 21.5 48 48 48h352c26.5 0 48-21.5 48-48V272c0-26.5-21.5-48-48-48zm-104 0H152v-72c0-39.7 32.3-72 72-72s72 32.3 72 72v72z"></path></svg></a>0 miles<a class="leaflet-control-expandable-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Draw" data-draggable="false"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="shapes" class="svg-inline--fa fa-shapes fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M128,256A128,128,0,1,0,256,384,128,128,0,0,0,128,256Zm379-54.86L400.07,18.29a37.26,37.26,0,0,0-64.14,0L229,201.14C214.76,225.52,232.58,256,261.09,256H474.91C503.42,256,521.24,225.52,507,201.14ZM480,288H320a32,32,0,0,0-32,32V480a32,32,0,0,0,32,32H480a32,32,0,0,0,32-32V320A32,32,0,0,0,480,288Z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-has-actions leaflet-control-draw-polygon-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Polygon"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="draw-polygon" class="svg-inline--fa fa-draw-polygon fa-w-14" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M384 352c-.35 0-.67.1-1.02.1l-39.2-65.32c5.07-9.17 8.22-19.56 8.22-30.78s-3.14-21.61-8.22-30.78l39.2-65.32c.35.01.67.1 1.02.1 35.35 0 64-28.65 64-64s-28.65-64-64-64c-23.63 0-44.04 12.95-55.12 32H119.12C108.04 44.95 87.63 32 64 32 28.65 32 0 60.65 0 96c0 23.63 12.95 44.04 32 55.12v209.75C12.95 371.96 0 392.37 0 416c0 35.35 28.65 64 64 64 23.63 0 44.04-12.95 55.12-32h209.75c11.09 19.05 31.49 32 55.12 32 35.35 0 64-28.65 64-64 .01-35.35-28.64-64-63.99-64zm-288 8.88V151.12A63.825 63.825 0 0 0 119.12 128h208.36l-38.46 64.1c-.35-.01-.67-.1-1.02-.1-35.35 0-64 28.65-64 64s28.65 64 64 64c.35 0 .67-.1 1.02-.1l38.46 64.1H119.12A63.748 63.748 0 0 0 96 360.88zM272 256c0-8.82 7.18-16 16-16s16 7.18 16 16-7.18 16-16 16-16-7.18-16-16zM400 96c0 8.82-7.18 16-16 16s-16-7.18-16-16 7.18-16 16-16 16 7.18 16 16zM64 80c8.82 0 16 7.18 16 16s-7.18 16-16 16-16-7.18-16-16 7.18-16 16-16zM48 416c0-8.82 7.18-16 16-16s16 7.18 16 16-7.18 16-16 16-16-7.18-16-16zm336 16c-8.82 0-16-7.18-16-16s7.18-16 16-16 16 7.18 16 16-7.18 16-16 16z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-complete-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Finish"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="check" class="svg-inline--fa fa-check fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M173.898 439.404l-166.4-166.4c-9.997-9.997-9.997-26.206 0-36.204l36.203-36.204c9.997-9.998 26.207-9.998 36.204 0L192 312.69 432.095 72.596c9.997-9.997 26.207-9.997 36.204 0l36.203 36.204c9.997 9.997 9.997 26.206 0 36.204l-294.4 294.401c-9.998 9.997-26.207 9.997-36.204-.001z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-undo-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Undo"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="undo-alt" class="svg-inline--fa fa-undo-alt fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M255.545 8c-66.269.119-126.438 26.233-170.86 68.685L48.971 40.971C33.851 25.851 8 36.559 8 57.941V192c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h134.059c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-41.75-41.75c30.864-28.899 70.801-44.907 113.23-45.273 92.398-.798 170.283 73.977 169.484 169.442C423.236 348.009 349.816 424 256 424c-41.127 0-79.997-14.678-110.63-41.556-4.743-4.161-11.906-3.908-16.368.553L89.34 422.659c-4.872 4.872-4.631 12.815.482 17.433C133.798 479.813 192.074 504 256 504c136.966 0 247.999-111.033 248-247.998C504.001 119.193 392.354 7.755 255.545 8z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-cancel-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Cancel"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="times-circle" class="svg-inline--fa fa-times-circle fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 8C119 8 8 119 8 256s111 248 248 248 248-111 248-248S393 8 256 8zm121.6 313.1c4.7 4.7 4.7 12.3 0 17L338 377.6c-4.7 4.7-12.3 4.7-17 0L256 312l-65.1 65.6c-4.7 4.7-12.3 4.7-17 0L134.4 338c-4.7-4.7-4.7-12.3 0-17l65.6-65-65.6-65.1c-4.7-4.7-4.7-12.3 0-17l39.6-39.6c4.7-4.7 12.3-4.7 17 0l65 65.7 65.1-65.6c4.7-4.7 12.3-4.7 17 0l39.6 39.6c4.7 4.7 4.7 12.3 0 17L312 256l65.6 65.1z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-has-actions leaflet-control-draw-rectangle-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Rectangle"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="vector-square" class="svg-inline--fa fa-vector-square fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M512 128V32c0-17.67-14.33-32-32-32h-96c-17.67 0-32 14.33-32 32H160c0-17.67-14.33-32-32-32H32C14.33 0 0 14.33 0 32v96c0 17.67 14.33 32 32 32v192c-17.67 0-32 14.33-32 32v96c0 17.67 14.33 32 32 32h96c17.67 0 32-14.33 32-32h192c0 17.67 14.33 32 32 32h96c17.67 0 32-14.33 32-32v-96c0-17.67-14.33-32-32-32V160c17.67 0 32-14.33 32-32zm-96-64h32v32h-32V64zM64 64h32v32H64V64zm32 384H64v-32h32v32zm352 0h-32v-32h32v32zm-32-96h-32c-17.67 0-32 14.33-32 32v32H160v-32c0-17.67-14.33-32-32-32H96V160h32c17.67 0 32-14.33 32-32V96h192v32c0 17.67 14.33 32 32 32h32v192z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-undo-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Undo"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="undo-alt" class="svg-inline--fa fa-undo-alt fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M255.545 8c-66.269.119-126.438 26.233-170.86 68.685L48.971 40.971C33.851 25.851 8 36.559 8 57.941V192c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h134.059c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-41.75-41.75c30.864-28.899 70.801-44.907 113.23-45.273 92.398-.798 170.283 73.977 169.484 169.442C423.236 348.009 349.816 424 256 424c-41.127 0-79.997-14.678-110.63-41.556-4.743-4.161-11.906-3.908-16.368.553L89.34 422.659c-4.872 4.872-4.631 12.815.482 17.433C133.798 479.813 192.074 504 256 504c136.966 0 247.999-111.033 248-247.998C504.001 119.193 392.354 7.755 255.545 8z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-cancel-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Cancel"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="times-circle" class="svg-inline--fa fa-times-circle fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 8C119 8 8 119 8 256s111 248 248 248 248-111 248-248S393 8 256 8zm121.6 313.1c4.7 4.7 4.7 12.3 0 17L338 377.6c-4.7 4.7-12.3 4.7-17 0L256 312l-65.1 65.6c-4.7 4.7-12.3 4.7-17 0L134.4 338c-4.7-4.7-4.7-12.3 0-17l65.6-65-65.6-65.1c-4.7-4.7-4.7-12.3 0-17l39.6-39.6c4.7-4.7 12.3-4.7 17 0l65 65.7 65.1-65.6c4.7-4.7 12.3-4.7 17 0l39.6 39.6c4.7 4.7 4.7 12.3 0 17L312 256l65.6 65.1z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-has-actions leaflet-control-draw-polyline-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Polyline"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="project-diagram" class="svg-inline--fa fa-project-diagram fa-w-20" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M384 320H256c-17.67 0-32 14.33-32 32v128c0 17.67 14.33 32 32 32h128c17.67 0 32-14.33 32-32V352c0-17.67-14.33-32-32-32zM192 32c0-17.67-14.33-32-32-32H32C14.33 0 0 14.33 0 32v128c0 17.67 14.33 32 32 32h95.72l73.16 128.04C211.98 300.98 232.4 288 256 288h.28L192 175.51V128h224V64H192V32zM608 0H480c-17.67 0-32 14.33-32 32v128c0 17.67 14.33 32 32 32h128c17.67 0 32-14.33 32-32V32c0-17.67-14.33-32-32-32z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-complete-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Finish"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="check" class="svg-inline--fa fa-check fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M173.898 439.404l-166.4-166.4c-9.997-9.997-9.997-26.206 0-36.204l36.203-36.204c9.997-9.998 26.207-9.998 36.204 0L192 312.69 432.095 72.596c9.997-9.997 26.207-9.997 36.204 0l36.203 36.204c9.997 9.997 9.997 26.206 0 36.204l-294.4 294.401c-9.998 9.997-26.207 9.997-36.204-.001z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-arrow-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Add Arrows to Line"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="arrow-up" class="svg-inline--fa fa-arrow-up fa-w-14" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M34.9 289.5l-22.2-22.2c-9.4-9.4-9.4-24.6 0-33.9L207 39c9.4-9.4 24.6-9.4 33.9 0l194.3 194.3c9.4 9.4 9.4 24.6 0 33.9L413 289.4c-9.5 9.5-25 9.3-34.3-.4L264 168.6V456c0 13.3-10.7 24-24 24h-32c-13.3 0-24-10.7-24-24V168.6L69.2 289.1c-9.3 9.8-24.8 10-34.3.4z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-undo-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Undo"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="undo-alt" class="svg-inline--fa fa-undo-alt fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M255.545 8c-66.269.119-126.438 26.233-170.86 68.685L48.971 40.971C33.851 25.851 8 36.559 8 57.941V192c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h134.059c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-41.75-41.75c30.864-28.899 70.801-44.907 113.23-45.273 92.398-.798 170.283 73.977 169.484 169.442C423.236 348.009 349.816 424 256 424c-41.127 0-79.997-14.678-110.63-41.556-4.743-4.161-11.906-3.908-16.368.553L89.34 422.659c-4.872 4.872-4.631 12.815.482 17.433C133.798 479.813 192.074 504 256 504c136.966 0 247.999-111.033 248-247.998C504.001 119.193 392.354 7.755 255.545 8z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-cancel-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Cancel"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="times-circle" class="svg-inline--fa fa-times-circle fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 8C119 8 8 119 8 256s111 248 248 248 248-111 248-248S393 8 256 8zm121.6 313.1c4.7 4.7 4.7 12.3 0 17L338 377.6c-4.7 4.7-12.3 4.7-17 0L256 312l-65.1 65.6c-4.7 4.7-12.3 4.7-17 0L134.4 338c-4.7-4.7-4.7-12.3 0-17l65.6-65-65.6-65.1c-4.7-4.7-4.7-12.3 0-17l39.6-39.6c4.7-4.7 12.3-4.7 17 0l65 65.7 65.1-65.6c4.7-4.7 12.3-4.7 17 0l39.6 39.6c4.7 4.7 4.7 12.3 0 17L312 256l65.6 65.1z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-has-actions leaflet-control-draw-paint-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Color" style="color: #3388FF"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="circle" class="svg-inline--fa fa-circle fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 8C119 8 8 119 8 256s111 248 248 248 248-111 248-248S393 8 256 8z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-fill-color-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Fill Color"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="fill-drip" class="svg-inline--fa fa-fill-drip fa-w-18" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M512 320s-64 92.65-64 128c0 35.35 28.66 64 64 64s64-28.65 64-64-64-128-64-128zm-9.37-102.94L294.94 9.37C288.69 3.12 280.5 0 272.31 0s-16.38 3.12-22.62 9.37l-81.58 81.58L81.93 4.76c-6.25-6.25-16.38-6.25-22.62 0L36.69 27.38c-6.24 6.25-6.24 16.38 0 22.62l86.19 86.18-94.76 94.76c-37.49 37.48-37.49 98.26 0 135.75l117.19 117.19c18.74 18.74 43.31 28.12 67.87 28.12 24.57 0 49.13-9.37 67.87-28.12l221.57-221.57c12.5-12.5 12.5-32.75.01-45.25zm-116.22 70.97H65.93c1.36-3.84 3.57-7.98 7.43-11.83l13.15-13.15 81.61-81.61 58.6 58.6c12.49 12.49 32.75 12.49 45.24 0s12.49-32.75 0-45.24l-58.6-58.6 58.95-58.95 162.44 162.44-48.34 48.34z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-has-actions leaflet-control-draw-palette-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Color"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="palette" class="svg-inline--fa fa-palette fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M204.3 5C104.9 24.4 24.8 104.3 5.2 203.4c-37 187 131.7 326.4 258.8 306.7 41.2-6.4 61.4-54.6 42.5-91.7-23.1-45.4 9.9-98.4 60.9-98.4h79.7c35.8 0 64.8-29.6 64.9-65.3C511.5 97.1 368.1-26.9 204.3 5zM96 320c-17.7 0-32-14.3-32-32s14.3-32 32-32 32 14.3 32 32-14.3 32-32 32zm32-128c-17.7 0-32-14.3-32-32s14.3-32 32-32 32 14.3 32 32-14.3 32-32 32zm128-64c-17.7 0-32-14.3-32-32s14.3-32 32-32 32 14.3 32 32-14.3 32-32 32zm128 64c-17.7 0-32-14.3-32-32s14.3-32 32-32 32 14.3 32 32-14.3 32-32 32z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-has-actions leaflet-control-draw-drag-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Move Shapes"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="arrows-alt" class="svg-inline--fa fa-arrows-alt fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M352.201 425.775l-79.196 79.196c-9.373 9.373-24.568 9.373-33.941 0l-79.196-79.196c-15.119-15.119-4.411-40.971 16.971-40.97h51.162L228 284H127.196v51.162c0 21.382-25.851 32.09-40.971 16.971L7.029 272.937c-9.373-9.373-9.373-24.569 0-33.941L86.225 159.8c15.119-15.119 40.971-4.411 40.971 16.971V228H228V127.196h-51.23c-21.382 0-32.09-25.851-16.971-40.971l79.196-79.196c9.373-9.373 24.568-9.373 33.941 0l79.196 79.196c15.119 15.119 4.411 40.971-16.971 40.971h-51.162V228h100.804v-51.162c0-21.382 25.851-32.09 40.97-16.971l79.196 79.196c9.373 9.373 9.373 24.569 0 33.941L425.773 352.2c-15.119 15.119-40.971 4.411-40.97-16.971V284H284v100.804h51.23c21.382 0 32.09 25.851 16.971 40.971z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-complete-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Finish"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="check" class="svg-inline--fa fa-check fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M173.898 439.404l-166.4-166.4c-9.997-9.997-9.997-26.206 0-36.204l36.203-36.204c9.997-9.998 26.207-9.998 36.204 0L192 312.69 432.095 72.596c9.997-9.997 26.207-9.997 36.204 0l36.203 36.204c9.997 9.997 9.997 26.206 0 36.204l-294.4 294.401c-9.998 9.997-26.207 9.997-36.204-.001z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-has-actions leaflet-control-draw-trash-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Delete Shapes"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="trash" class="svg-inline--fa fa-trash fa-w-14" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M432 32H312l-9.4-18.7A24 24 0 0 0 281.1 0H166.8a23.72 23.72 0 0 0-21.4 13.3L136 32H16A16 16 0 0 0 0 48v32a16 16 0 0 0 16 16h416a16 16 0 0 0 16-16V48a16 16 0 0 0-16-16zM53.2 467a48 48 0 0 0 47.9 45h245.8a48 48 0 0 0 47.9-45L416 128H32z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-complete-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Finish"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="check" class="svg-inline--fa fa-check fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M173.898 439.404l-166.4-166.4c-9.997-9.997-9.997-26.206 0-36.204l36.203-36.204c9.997-9.998 26.207-9.998 36.204 0L192 312.69 432.095 72.596c9.997-9.997 26.207-9.997 36.204 0l36.203 36.204c9.997 9.997 9.997 26.206 0 36.204l-294.4 294.401c-9.998 9.997-26.207 9.997-36.204-.001z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-has-actions leaflet-control-save-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Export Drawing to GeoJSON"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="save" class="svg-inline--fa fa-save fa-w-14" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M433.941 129.941l-83.882-83.882A48 48 0 0 0 316.118 32H48C21.49 32 0 53.49 0 80v352c0 26.51 21.49 48 48 48h352c26.51 0 48-21.49 48-48V163.882a48 48 0 0 0-14.059-33.941zM224 416c-35.346 0-64-28.654-64-64 0-35.346 28.654-64 64-64s64 28.654 64 64c0 35.346-28.654 64-64 64zm96-304.52V212c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12H76c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12V108c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h228.52c3.183 0 6.235 1.264 8.485 3.515l3.48 3.48A11.996 11.996 0 0 1 320 111.48z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-draw-done-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Done"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="check" class="svg-inline--fa fa-check fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M173.898 439.404l-166.4-166.4c-9.997-9.997-9.997-26.206 0-36.204l36.203-36.204c9.997-9.998 26.207-9.998 36.204 0L192 312.69 432.095 72.596c9.997-9.997 26.207-9.997 36.204 0l36.203 36.204c9.997 9.997 9.997 26.206 0 36.204l-294.4 294.401c-9.998 9.997-26.207 9.997-36.204-.001z"></path></svg></a><a class="leaflet-control-save-param-icon" href="about:blank#" aria-label="Save Parameters to View"><svg aria-hidden="true" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="save" class="svg-inline--fa fa-save fa-w-14" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M433.941 129.941l-83.882-83.882A48 48 0 0 0 316.118 32H48C21.49 32 0 53.49 0 80v352c0 26.51 21.49 48 48 48h352c26.51 0 48-21.49 48-48V163.882a48 48 0 0 0-14.059-33.941zM224 416c-35.346 0-64-28.654-64-64 0-35.346 28.654-64 64-64s64 28.654 64 64c0 35.346-28.654 64-64 64zm96-304.52V212c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12H76c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12V108c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h228.52c3.183 0 6.235 1.264 8.485 3.515l3.48 3.48A11.996 11.996 0 0 1 320 111.48z"></path></svg></a><a href="https://leafletjs.com" title="A JS library for interactive maps">Leaflet</a><br>Khorvaire is the continent where most adventures in Eberron begin—a land rich in history, magic, and intrigue. Thanks to the tireless efforts of House Sivis and House Orien, Khorvaire is well-mapped and connected, making it the most navigable of Eberron’s continents. However, even though many regions are well-known, there are still uncharted corners filled with ancient secrets, wild dangers, and mysteries waiting to be uncovered.<br><br>Humans make up the majority of Khorvaire’s population, but this diverse continent is home to a wide array of cultures, races, and creatures. Once united under the Kingdom of Galifar, Khorvaire is now divided into various nations, some as old as history itself, others forged in the crucible of the Last War. While peace reigns for now, the scars of the war are still fresh, and tensions simmer just beneath the surface.<br>Khorvaire’s Nations are connected by a well-maintained system of roads, along with the lightning rail of House Orien that spans the central nations, allowing swift travel between major cities. For those with deeper pockets, the airships of House Lyrandar offer the fastest, albeit most expensive, means of travel. Whether by land, rail, or air, Khorvaire’s network of transportation keeps its fractured nations tied together, though rivalries and suspicions remain strong.<br><br>Everyday life in Khorvaire reflects the continent’s complexity. The lingering effects of the Last War, the dominance of the dragonmarked houses, and the omnipresence of magic all shape the culture of its nations.<br><br>Khorvaire's vast population is multilingual, with Common serving as the trade language and most widely spoken tongue. However, regional languages like Dwarvish in the Mror Holds, Giant in Xen'drik, and Goblin in Darguun and the Shadow Marches reflect the deep history of the continent. The naming conventions of Khorvaire also vary by region and culture, with nobles adding the "ir'" prefix to their family names, and dragonmarked heirs using the "d'" prefix to signify their status.<br><br>The common calendar of Khorvaire is based on the twelve moons of Eberron, with each month corresponding to the closest moon. The timeline begins with the foundation of the Kingdom of Galifar, measured in YK (Years of the Kingdom). By default, most campaigns in Khorvaire begin in the year 998 YK, just two years after the Treaty of Thronehold ended the Last War, though the continent remains on edge.<br><br>Trade and commerce in Khorvaire are built on a stable system of currency established during the Galifar era. Coins such as the gold galifar (gp), silver sovereign (sp), and copper crown (cp) are still used across the nations, ensuring a standardized economy. Wealthy merchants and nobles often use letters of credit backed by the bankers of the Mror Holds, while common folk still use coins for day-to-day transactions.<br><br>Let’s explore each country a little more, moving from west to east, though not in any particular order of importance. Keep in mind that the original empire, Galifar, which was shattered by the Last War, consisted of five core nations: Aundair, Thrane, Breland, Cyre, and Karrnath. These are still referred to as the Five Nations, and their legacy continues to shape the politics and culture of Khorvaire today.<br><br>The Shadow Marches are a desolate, swampy region filled with moors and mystery, home to the largest half-orc population in Khorvaire. Though not a formal nation, the Marches are primarily known for their rich deposits of Eberron dragonshards, making them a hub for prospectors. The orcs and humans here live in isolated tribes, with a long history tied to the ancient struggle against the daelkyr, aberrant creatures who left behind madness and twisted monsters in the swamps. House Tharashk, a half-orc house known for the Mark of Finding, dominates the region's commerce through Zarash’ak, their unofficial capital. The Shadow Marches are also the birthplace of the Gatekeepers, a druidic sect that continues to protect the land from extraplanar threats, though dangerous cults and daelkyr relics still linger in the shadows.<br><br>A monstrous nation ruled by the Daughters of Sora Kell, Droaam is a land where creatures like ogres, trolls, harpies, gnolls, and medusas thrive. Formed just over a decade ago, this wild territory west of the Graywall Mountains has quickly gained strength and stability under the hags' leadership, despite not being recognized by the Treaty of Thronehold. Its capital, the Great Crag, is growing, along with the frontier cities like Graywall. House Tharashk partners with Droaam to export monstrous mercenaries and the rare byeshk ore. Though most of Khorvaire dismisses Droaam as a temporary alliance, the nation's power continues to rise, making the rest of the continent uneasy.<br><br>The Demon Wastes is a desolate and dangerous region, where rivers of lava cut through blackened plains and volcanic glass. Once home to powerful fiends and ancient demon lords, this cursed land is now inhabited by fiends, including devils, rakshasas, and demons, as well as the brutal Carrion Tribes, who worship these dark powers. The only barrier keeping these evils from spreading is the Labyrinth, a series of canyons patrolled by the Ghaash'kala, a tribe of orcs sworn to contain the horrors of the Wastes. Though its ruins may hold ancient treasures, the Demon Wastes remain a deadly and treacherous place where few dare to venture.<br><br>The Eldeen Reaches are a vast, loosely governed region of fertile farmlands and the untamed Towering Wood. Once part of Aundair, the farmers of eastern Aundair seceded during the Last War with the help of druids and rangers, forming their own nation. The Reaches are home to a diverse population, including humans, shifters, and nomadic druidic circles. The Wardens of the Wood, the largest druid sect, maintain peace and harmony, guided by the Great Druid, an awakened greatpine named Oalian. Known for agriculture and animal husbandry, the Reaches blend natural magic into everyday life, where druids advise communities, and awakened beasts and fey creatures are part of the society. Although peaceful, the Reachers remain wary of Aundair and prepare for a possible conflict to defend their independence.<br><br>Aundair is a kingdom steeped in magic, ruled by the ambitious Queen Aurala ir’Wynarn. Known for its arcane prowess, Aundair is home to the prestigious magical academy of Arcanix, and the floating towers that symbolize its mastery over wizardry. The majority of its population consists of humans, with half-elves and elves often found among the nation’s scholars and nobles. Dwarves and gnomes also contribute to the kingdom’s vibrant academic and artistic communities. Aundairians value knowledge, finesse, and fashion, and their land is known for producing fine wines, cheeses, and grain. Despite its small size, Aundair held its own in the Last War through superior magical power. However, tensions linger with both Thrane and the Eldeen Reaches, and many Aundairians still seek to reclaim lost territories. Magic permeates everyday life, and Aundair's elegant culture stands in stark contrast to the scars left by the war.<br><br>Thrane is a human theocracy ruled by the Church of the Silver Flame, with 11-year-old Jaela Daran as the divine Keeper of the Flame. The Silver Flame’s purpose is to defend the innocent from supernatural threats, making Thrane a beacon of faith and righteousness. While the faith is central, not all Thranes uphold its ideals—zealots seek to unite Khorvaire under the Flame, while corrupt priests pursue power. The nation is home to many clerics and paladins, though magewrights and wizards are less common. Thrane’s deep faith unites its people, but its strict adherence to the Silver Flame also fosters distrust toward necromancers, warlocks, and practitioners of dark magic.<br><br>Ruled by the popular King Boranel, Breland is a powerful and industrialized nation, known for its pragmatism, innovation, and intrigue. It boasts one of the most diverse populations in Khorvaire, with humans, half-elves, and halflings making up the majority, while its cities—especially Sharn—also welcome a variety of monstrous races, including goblins, ogres, orcs, and even harpies and gargoyles from nearby Droaam. Breland's large population and vast resources make it a hub of industry and espionage, but also a hotbed for organized crime. The nation played a significant role in the Last War and is home to the largest number of Cyran refugees. Though King Boranel remains beloved, some citizens advocate for a shift toward democracy once he passes, leaving Breland’s future uncertain.<br><br>Zilargo is the gnomish homeland, a peaceful-seeming paradise known for its brilliant minds, elemental binding, and fine alchemy. The Library of Korranberg, the largest repository of knowledge in Khorvaire, and the Korranberg Chronicle, the continent’s most popular newspaper, are based here. Despite the idyllic appearance, Zil society is a web of intrigue, with every gnome seemingly involved in one scheme or another. The Trust, a ruthless secret police force, eliminates threats to society with preemptive efficiency, ensuring the streets remain safe. As long as one follows the unwritten rules of Zil intrigue, life in Zilargo is serene—but crossing the Trust is a fatal mistake.<br><br>Darguun is a volatile and young nation ruled by the hobgoblin leader Lhesh Haruuc Sharaat'kor. Once part of Cyre, Darguun was seized during the Last War by the goblinoid mercenaries who had fought for the Five Nations. Now home to goblins, hobgoblins, and bugbears, the country is known for its fierce warriors and mercenary forces. While recognized as a nation under the Treaty of Thronehold, Darguun operates on its own terms, and its laws differ greatly from those of other treaty nations. Mercenaries, adventurers, and traders may find opportunities in this land, but it remains dangerous and unpredictable.<br><br>Once the shining heart of the Kingdom of Galifar, Cyre was obliterated by a magical cataclysm known as the Mourning. Now, the Mournland is a desolate wasteland of twisted magic and ghostly ruins, where wounds never heal and the dead do not decompose. Mutated monsters, living spells, and other strange dangers roam this cursed land, which remains largely uninhabited save for some warforged factions, including the enigmatic Lord of Blades. The survivors of Cyre, scattered across Khorvaire, dream of rebuilding their lost nation, though many simply strive to survive in a world that views them with a mix of pity and suspicion.<br><br>Karrnath is a grim and disciplined human kingdom ruled by King Kaius III, known for its military prowess and strict laws. During the Last War, the nation famously used undead troops—skeletons and zombies—raised by the necromancers of the Blood of Vol to bolster their armies. While the undead still serve as laborers and guards, Kaius has distanced himself from the Blood of Vol, creating tension between its followers and traditionalists who see the use of undead as a stain on Karrnath's honor. The people of Karrnath, predominantly humans with smaller populations of dwarves and half-elves, are tough and resilient, used to enduring harsh winters and strict rationing. Military training is a source of great pride, and the Rekkenmark Academy remains the premier institute for military officers. Though the war has ended, many Karrns still believe they would have won had it continued, and the nation remains on high alert, wary of unrest from within and without.<br><br>The Talenta Plains are home to the nomadic halflings, known for their close bond with the dinosaurs they ride and raise. These wild plains are vast, filled with roaming dinosaur herds and the halfling tribes that live off the land, following the guidance of their chieftains and shamans. Life here revolves around hunting, tradition, and a deep reverence for ancestral and natural spirits. While the halflings united under Lathon Halpum during the Last War to defend their way of life, they now face challenges as more outsiders cross the Plains, bringing both trade and conflict. Despite being recognized as a nation under the Treaty of Thronehold, the halflings must now decide if they will embrace change or push back against the encroaching influences.<br><br>Valenar is a land claimed by the warrior elves of Tairnadal during the Last War. Known for their unmatched cavalry and devotion to the arts of war, the Valenar elves took the region from Cyre, invoking ancient claims to the land. Their kingdom is primarily composed of open plains ideal for breeding their famous horses, with harsher environments like the Blade Desert serving as natural borders. Valenar elves live for battle and adventure, frequently patrolling their land in warbands or seeking challenges abroad. The daily affairs of the kingdom are managed by half-elves, while Cyran humans, the former inhabitants of the region, continue their lives under new rulers. Though Valenar is now a recognized sovereign nation, the elves remain focused on their next conflict, pushing the limits of peace as they seek worthy opponents.<br><br>A rugged frontier on the edge of Khorvaire, Q'barra was initially settled by those seeking refuge from the Last War, including loyalists to the old Galifar Empire and Cyran refugees. Its dense jungles and untamed wilderness hide both danger and opportunity. While human settlements are few, the region is rich with deposits of Eberron dragonshards, attracting prospectors, fortune-seekers, and criminals alike. Beneath the surface, however, Q'barra is home to ancient civilizations of lizardfolk and dragonborn, including the Cold Sun Federation and the hostile Poison Dusk tribes. Tensions between the settlers and the indigenous "scales" continue to rise, particularly as treaties are violated and settlers push deeper into lands tied to fiendish powers from the Age of Demons.<br><br>The mountainous home of the dwarves, the Mror Holds is a land of wealth and industry. Known for its vast metal mines and advanced metalwork, the dwarves of Mror have a reputation as master merchants and craftsmen. After discovering ancient dwarven ruins deep within the Ironroot Mountains, the clans uncovered riches and powerful artifacts, but also awakened an ancient evil: the daelkyr lord Dyrrn the Corruptor. Now, the dwarves battle aberrations in the depths of the Realm Below while continuing to mine its treasures. The Holds are a loose confederation of twelve noble clans, each governing a hold, but the threat of the daelkyr and differing views on how to deal with the aberrations—some clans embracing their power, others shunning it—threatens their unity.<br><br>The Lhazaar Principalities are a loose alliance of pirate lords, merchant princes, and sea barons who control the northeastern coastline of Khorvaire. Recognized as a nation under the Treaty of Thronehold, each island domain operates independently, often feuding with one another. The Lhazaar are the best sailors in Khorvaire, serving as privateers during the Last War and continuing piracy alongside legitimate merchant trade. Leadership is fluid, with anyone able to rise from sailor to prince through cunning and strength. High Prince Ryger ir'Wynarn of Regalport seeks to unite the principalities under his rule, but most princes value their independence. The Lhazaar Principalities also have a significant changeling population and a number of foundlings with the Mark of Storm, who are unaffiliated with House Lyrandar but seek to acquire airships for their own gain.]]></description><link>dm\sessions\session-0\3.-eberron's-places.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">DM/Sessions/Session 0/3. Eberron's Places.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 16:03:58 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\map-eberron.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib\media\map-eberron.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[4. Eberron's People]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Eberron is a diverse place where many different races coexist, each bringing unique cultures, histories, and abilities to the world. From the bustling cities of Khorvaire to the untamed frontiers, every race has carved out its place in the aftermath of the Last War. With the rise of dragonmarked houses and the ancient struggles of long-lost empires, the people of Eberron are shaped by their history and their roles in this complex and magical world.<br><br>Most of the races in Eberron have similarities to their standard counterparts in D&amp;D, but there are notable differences that give them a unique flavor. Additionally, many races are tied to specific dragonmarks, which grant them special powers and influence over various industries and guilds across the continent.<br><br><img alt="Image - Density - Humans.png" src="lib\media\image-density-humans.png"><br>Humans are the most common race in Eberron and are found in the majority of its kingdoms. They are versatile and ambitious, with some bearing dragonmarks that grant them great power. Humans can have the Mark of Finding, Mark of Handling, Mark of Making, Mark of Passage, or Mark of Sentinel, and they dominate most political, social, and economic landscapes, especially in the Five Nations.<br><br><img alt="Image - Density - Half-Elves.png" src="lib\media\image-density-half-elves.png"><br>In Eberron, half-elves are known as the Khoravar, a distinct race with their own culture. While they have some similarities to humans and elves, they stand apart with their unique identities. Half-elves can bear the Mark of Detection or the Mark of Storm, and many have positions of influence within their dragonmarked houses or serve as intermediaries between different cultures.<br><br><img alt="Image - Density - Half-Orcs.png" src="lib\media\image-density-half-orcs.png"><br>Half-orcs in Eberron trace their lineage back to ancient struggles with aberrant invaders from another plane. They often live in frontier areas, working as prospectors, trappers, or druids. Many have the Mark of Finding, which aids them in their search for dragonshards, valuable magical crystals scattered across Eberron.<br><br><img alt="Image - Density - Halflings.png" src="lib\media\image-density-halflings.png"><br>Halflings in Eberron fall into two distinct categories. There are city-dwelling halflings who often work as innkeepers, healers, or merchants, using the Mark of Healing or Mark of Hospitality to support their work. Then there are the nomadic halflings of the Talenta Plains, who tame and ride dinosaurs, living a more primal and tribal lifestyle as fierce hunters and ambushers.<br><br><img alt="Image - Density - Gnomes.png" src="lib\media\image-density-gnomes.png"><br>Gnomes in Eberron are known for their cunning and mastery of elemental binding, a vital magical technology. They play key roles in banking, magic, and politics, though much of their influence is kept secret. Gnomes can bear the Mark of Scribing, which enhances their roles as scribes, chroniclers, and agents of subterfuge. Their homeland, Zilargo, is a place of intrigue, hidden power, and conspiracy.<br><br><img alt="Image - Density -Elves.png" src="lib\media\image-density-elves.png"><br>There are three main groups of elves in Eberron. The Aereni elves on the island of Aerenal revere their ancestors and maintain ancient traditions, with some serving the mysterious Undying Court. The Valenar elves are warrior nomads who staked a claim on Khorvaire during the Last War, renowned for their cavalry and martial skill. The Phiarlan and Thuranni elves bear the Mark of Shadow and run powerful guilds focusing on entertainment, espionage, and intrigue.<br><br><img alt="Image - Density - Dwarves.png" src="lib\media\image-density-dwarves.png"><br>Dwarves in Eberron are master miners and craftsmen, living in powerful holds in the Mror Mountains. Their Mark of Warding allows them to excel in banking, defense, and protective magic. Dwarves also have a history of delving deep into the earth, uncovering both riches and ancient dangers, which have given rise to conflicts with powerful aberrations.<br><br>Changelings are shapeshifters, descendants of doppelgangers and humans, who can alter their appearance at will. This makes them natural spies, infiltrators, and diplomats, though their ability to hide in plain sight often leads to suspicion. Changelings never bear dragonmarks but are valued for their versatility and adaptability.<br><br>Shifters are the descendants of lycanthropes and humans, able to temporarily take on animalistic traits, such as growing claws, increasing speed, or heightening their senses. Shifters are often found in rural or wild areas, acting as rangers or hunters, and are closely tied to the natural world.<br><br>Warforged are living constructs, originally created to serve as soldiers during the Last War. Now that the war is over, they seek purpose beyond the battlefield, struggling with questions of identity and freedom. As sentient beings made of metal and magic, warforged don't need to eat or sleep, but they face widespread prejudice despite being granted full citizenship after the Treaty of Thronehold.<br><br>Dragonborn in Eberron trace their ancestry to Argonnessen, the homeland of dragons, though most in Khorvaire come from Q’barra, where they live alongside lizardfolk in the jungles. These dragonborn are believed to be descendants of an ancient empire and serve as guardians of their draconic heritage, with a deep connection to the Draconic Prophecy. Their society emphasizes honor, tradition, and service, and while they lack dragonmarks, their innate magic makes them powerful sorcerers and warriors. Some dragonborn venture out as mercenaries or explorers, seeking to unlock the secrets of their draconic legacy and protect the world from ancient threats.<br><br>Tieflings in Eberron descend from humans whose bloodlines were tainted by fiendish pacts, particularly those from the Venomous Demesne in Droaam, where ancient families fled the influence of demons and devils in Sarlona. While often viewed with suspicion due to their infernal ancestry, tieflings are not inherently evil, though their connection to dark magic is undeniable. Many tieflings become powerful sorcerers, warlocks, or rogues, using their fiendish heritage to gain power in a world that frequently distrusts them. Despite having no dragonmarks, their infernal bloodline grants them unique abilities, making them influential players in Eberron's politics and intrigue.<br><br>The population demographics of Khorvaire are diverse, though exact numbers are difficult to determine. No official census has ever been conducted, and the upheaval caused by the Last War further complicated matters. Scholars, however, have been able to estimate the rough distribution of species across the continent, excluding the underdark region known as Khyber and other continents like Aerenal. These estimates reflect only the known populations on Khorvaire itself and highlight the presence of both common races and the more exotic inhabitants of the land.<br><br>
<br>Humans: 43%
<br>Dwarves: 9.3%
<br>Half-elves: 8.2%
<br>Gnomes: 6.5%
<br>Halflings: 6.3%
<br>Elves: 5.6%
<br>Orcs: 4.9%
<br>Goblins: 2.9%
<br>Changelings: 1.7%
<br>Hobgoblins: 1.5%
<br>Shifters: 1.1%
<br>Lizardfolk: 0.8%
<br>Kobolds: 0.7%
<br>Bugbears: 0.7%
<br>Half-orcs: 0.3%
<br>Warforged: Minimal
<br>Other: 3.8%
<br>Goblinoids<br>
<img alt="Image - Density - Goblinoids.png" src="lib\media\image-density-goblinoids.png">]]></description><link>dm\sessions\session-0\4.-eberron's-people.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">DM/Sessions/Session 0/4. Eberron's People.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 16:25:04 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\image-density-humans.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib\media\image-density-humans.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5. Developing Your Backstory]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Now that we’ve explored Eberron’s rich history, diverse locations, and the unique people who populate its vast landscapes, it’s time to anchor your character within this living world. Each adventurer in Eberron has a story, shaped by the Last War, the shifting politics of the Five Nations, and the mystical forces that weave through their lives. This is your opportunity to craft a character deeply connected to this setting, whose goals, alliances, and past experiences are integral to their journey.<br>In this part, we will focus on how your character’s past is intertwined with the people and events around them. Whether shaped by the shared trauma of the Last War or driven by personal ambitions, your character’s backstory will provide the foundation for their future in Eberron. To help guide you through this process, we will cover the following topics:<br>
<br>Setting the Scene: Understand the current state of the world and where the campaign begins.
<br>Your Group Patron: Korranberg Chronicle: Discover your shared patron and how it ties your party together.
<br>Choosing Your Class: Select the class that defines your character’s abilities and role in the world.
<br>Choosing Your Species: Choose a species that shapes your character’s culture, history, and worldview.
<br>Choosing Your Alignment: Decide on an alignment that reflects your character’s moral compass while fitting with the group dynamics.
<br>Exploring Faith and Beliefs: Determine the role of religion or philosophy in your character’s life and their connection to Eberron’s many belief systems.
<br>Your Role in the Last War: Reflect on how the Last War affected your character and their journey after the conflict.
<br>Creating Your Character’s Background: Build or select a background that summarizes your character’s experiences and the skills they’ve gained.
<br>Establishing Character Goals: Set long-term, mid-term, and short-term goals that will drive your character’s actions and decisions.
<br>Determining Connections with Other Characters: Explore potential relationships and shared histories with other party members to create a cohesive group.
<br>As you develop your character, these sections will guide you in crafting a backstory that enriches your role in the world of Eberron, ensuring that your adventurer is fully integrated into its complex, magical, and politically charged environment.<br><br>The campaign begins two years after the end of the Last War. It is the month of Therendor, early spring, when the world seems to wake from its winter slumber. The trees along the streets and hillsides are budding with fresh green leaves, while wildflowers bloom in patches of vibrant color across the plains. The chill of winter lingers in the air, but each day grows warmer, with the scent of damp earth and new growth heavy on the breeze.<br>You find yourselves on Mol, the 2nd, the start of a typical week. The streets of the cities in Khorvaire hum with the usual activity, but the two-year anniversary of the Day of Mourning still lingers in your mind. It was only weeks ago, on 20 Olarune, that Khorvaire remembered the catastrophic event—the day Cyre was swallowed by a strange and terrible power. For most, it is a day to mourn the countless lives lost and the nation wiped from the map. But for survivors of Cyre, it is a scar that never fully heals. Every year, Cyrans gather to sing the old songs, to speak the names of the fallen, and to share stories of their once-great kingdom. Yet, not all of these gatherings are peaceful. Some survivors still burn with anger, a fury that has boiled over into skirmishes and acts of violence during this grim anniversary.<br>The Sun's Blessing is only a few weeks away, on the 15th of Therendor—a festival dedicated to Dol Arrah, the goddess of honor and sunlight. It is a time when all are urged to set aside their differences and seek peace. It is a day when the city of Sharn, in particular, basks in the warmth of Dol Arrah's grace. Visitors and residents alike find a rare sense of calm, and the usual tensions of city life ease for a brief moment. Many look forward to the festival, a brief respite in the shadow of the war’s long aftermath.<br><br>DM RuleYour characters will begin their adventures as part of the Korranberg Chronicle, a renowned newspaper in Eberron.<br><br>In Eberron, patrons are powerful organizations, individuals, or institutions that guide and support adventurers in their quests. A patron gives your character a connection to the larger world, providing resources, direction, and a reason to take on missions. These patrons can range from dragonmarked houses and universities to noble rulers or secretive espionage agencies. Some patrons offer clear assignments and expect loyalty, while others act more as benefactors, allowing adventurers to pursue their own goals in exchange for occasional services. By working for a patron, your character gains purpose, opportunities, and connections that help shape their role in the world of Eberron.<br><br>The Korranberg Chronicle is Khorvaire's most prominent and widely read newspaper, known for its balanced reporting and in-depth coverage of key events, including the Last War. It is published three times a week (Mol, Wir, and Far) and features stories ranging from breaking news across the continent to royal proclamations, business announcements, and tales of daring adventurers. The Chronicle's vast readership is supported by a distribution partnership with House Orien, which ensures swift delivery to major cities and towns across Khorvaire via lightning rail and mail services.<br>Offices and Staff: The main office of the Korranberg Chronicle is based in Korranberg, but it maintains field offices throughout the Five Nations, Mror Holds, and Zilargo. These offices share space with House Sivis message stations, allowing for rapid communication between reporters and headquarters. Reporters, freelancers, and correspondents span the continent, often operating in dangerous or remote areas. The paper's editorial team, largely made up of Zil gnomes, is divided into ranks based on seniority, with junior editors covering local beats and senior editors overseeing broader topics such as crime or international affairs.<br>Allies: The Chronicle has built relationships with powerful allies, including House Orien, which aids in its distribution network, and House Sivis, facilitating fast communication between offices and reporters. Additionally, the gnome nation of Zilargo, where the Chronicle is based, provides political support and influence, especially when needed to protect its employees.<br>Enemies: The Korranberg Chronicle's commitment to the truth has made it enemies, including the Boromar Clan, which holds a grudge after a past expose led to major arrests within the crime syndicate. In Karrnath, King Kaius blames the paper for setbacks during peace talks, leading to harassment of its reporters. Meanwhile, House Thuranni, whose private affairs have been uncovered one too many times, refuses to cooperate with the Chronicle under any circumstances. Despite these challenges, the Korranberg Chronicle remains a trusted source of news and a powerful force in the dissemination of information across Eberron.<br><br>As members of the Korranberg Chronicle, your group enjoys several key benefits related to your role as reporters, adventurers, and investigators.<br>Compensation: Each member of your group earns 1 gp per day for providing the newspaper with publishable stories. This income is enough to sustain a modest lifestyle and covers your basic needs.<br>Expenses: In addition to your salary, the newspaper reimburses work-related expenses such as travel costs (for missions or interviews), meals during interviews, and communication fees (for couriers or House Sivis message stations). Excessive or frivolous expenses, however, might be refused.<br>Equipment: Your group can request access to the newspaper’s equipment, such as printing presses or communication tools. You may use this equipment for personal purposes, provided it doesn’t interfere with the newspaper’s operations or cross certain boundaries.<br>Press Access: Each member is issued identification papers that establish your role as a journalist. This status grants you some respect and can help you gain access to key figures, government officials, or other people of influence. However, revealing sensitive truths can put your group in danger from those who want to keep certain information hidden.<br>DM RuleAdd Press Identification Papers to your inventory.<br><br>Your role at the Korranberg Chronicle is more than just a job—it’s a vital part of your character’s identity and how they fit into Eberron’s complex world. As you craft your backstory, think about how your character’s experiences and personal goals are tied to their work at the Chronicle. Use the questions below to guide your decisions:<br>
<br>
What is your role at the newspaper?<br>
Are you a junior reporter just starting to make a name for yourself, or are you more of a behind-the-scenes investigator or researcher? Perhaps you're still trying to prove yourself by taking on dangerous assignments.

<br>
Where is your office?<br>
Do you work out of the main office in Korranberg, where you are close to the editorial board, or have you been assigned to a smaller, more remote location, such as a field office in Breland or Thrane? Consider why you were placed there—was it your choice, or were you sent away for specific reasons?

<br>
How did you transition from the Last War to the Chronicle?<br>
The Last War only ended two years ago, and its effects are still felt across Khorvaire. Whether you were a soldier, spy, or civilian, think about how your character went from those chaotic times to working as a journalist. Did you take this job to leave the war behind, seeking a quieter life, or did something you experienced during the war—perhaps a crucial event or shocking revelation—drive you to uncover the truth? Your role at the Chronicle could be a way to make sense of your past, or it might simply be the next chapter in a journey shaped by the war’s aftermath.

<br>
What have you accomplished during your time at the Chronicle?<br>
Have you had any small victories or published pieces that were well received? Maybe you broke a minor story or built a useful network of contacts. Alternatively, are you still struggling to get your first big break?

<br>
What is your journalistic focus?<br>
If you’re a reporter or investigator, do you have a particular beat or area of expertise? Examples might include uncovering political corruption, writing human-interest stories, or investigating the activities of dragonmarked houses. Your journalistic focus could help shape the type of adventures your character embarks on and the risks they take to uncover the truth. Some ideas are in the tables below.

<br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br>All classes from the 2024 Player's Handbook are available for this campaign. Classes found in other source material including Eberron sourcebooks are not available to play.<br>The available classes are:<br>
<br>Barbarian
<br>Bard
<br>Cleric
<br>Druid
<br>Fighter
<br>Monk
<br>Paladin
<br>Ranger
<br>Rogue
<br>Sorcerer
<br>Warlock
<br>Wizard
<br>DM RuleFor starting equipment, you should chose option B (the GP).<br><br>DM RuleYou may select any playable species from:

<br>The 2024 Player's Handbook

AND

<br>Any official Eberron sourcebooks, including::


<br>Eberron: Rising From the Last War (2019, WotC)
<br>Exploring Eberron (2020, Dungeon Masters Guild)
<br>Chronicles of Eberron (2022, Dungeon Masters Guild)
<br>Frontiers of Eberron: Quickstone (2024, Dungeon Masters Guild)
<br>TipThe DM can provide you with specific information about your species and its connection to Eberron's lore.<br>In Eberron, species are not just collections of traits—they are woven into the fabric of the world’s history, culture, and politics. Every species has a unique role in the world, from the industrious Gnomes of Zilargo to the mysterious Kalashtar, bound to spirits from the realm of dreams.<br><br>All species from the 2024 Player's Handbook are available in this campaign, these are:<br>
<br>Aasimar
<br>Dragonborn
<br>Dwarf
<br>Elf
<br>Gnome
<br>Goliath
<br>Halfling
<br>Human
<br>Orc
<br>Tiefling
<br><br>However, Eberron is also home to species found only within its lore, offering you the opportunity to explore characters shaped by the unique forces and factions of this world.<br>You may also choose from the species featured in the official Eberron sourcebooks, these are:<br>
<br>
Changeling<br>
Changelings are shapechangers who can alter their appearance at will, using this gift to create new personas or adopt masks for different situations, often living hidden among other races and following the unpredictable path of the Traveler.

<br>
Gargoyle<br>
Gargoyles are living stone beings originally crafted by Dhakaani goblins and animated by the daelkyr Orlassk, often taking on horned and winged forms, and driven by curiosity, guardianship, motion, or contemplation as they carve out a place in the world, particularly in Droaam.

<br>
Gnoll<br>
Gnolls are fierce and primal creatures, originally created as fiendish soldiers, but many have broken free of their demonic overlords, becoming loyal pack members and hunters, especially in Droaam, where some even harness their fiendish heritage as warlocks or demon-hunters.

<br>
Goblinoid (Goblin, Hobgoblin, Bugbear)<br>
Goblinoids, which include goblins, hobgoblins, and bugbears, once ruled Khorvaire under the mighty Dhakaani Empire, but today they are divided into distinct cultures such as the city-dwelling goblins, the Ghaal’dar tribes of Darguun, the raiding Marguul bugbears, and the secretive, martial Heirs of Dhakaan, each struggling to reclaim their former glory or carve out a place in a post-war world.

<br>
Half-Elf<br>
Half-elves, known as Khoravar, are the true children of Khorvaire, born from the union of humans and elves and raised in diverse communities with their own unique traditions, strengthened by the influence of the dragonmarked Houses Lyrandar and Medani.

<br>
Kalashtar<br>
Kalashtar are a unique people born from the union of humans and renegade quori spirits from the plane of dreams, granting them psionic abilities, a deep spiritual connection, and a constant struggle against the forces of the Dreaming Dark that seek their destruction.

<br>
Half-Orc<br>
Orcs and half-orcs in Eberron are descendants of ancient tribes who have long battled both the aberrations of the daelkyr and the fiends of the Demon Wastes, with many now playing key roles as Gatekeepers, mercenaries, or inquisitives working for House Tharashk, while others follow darker paths tied to the Dragon Below.

<br>
Harpy<br>
Harpies in Eberron are winged beings with the power to charm others through their magical voices, driven by intense passions and loyalty, with some serving the Daughters of Sora Kell in Droaam while others fiercely oppose them.

<br>
Medusa<br>
Medusas in Eberron are feared for their petrifying gaze and serve as powerful leaders in Droaam, where they are known for their skill in stonework and their devotion to the Dark Six, combining calm, calculating minds with a dangerous supernatural presence.

<br>
Shifter<br>
Shifters, sometimes called the "weretouched," are humanoids with a bestial heritage, able to temporarily enhance their animalistic traits through a transformation called shifting, embodying primal instincts and walking the line between civilization and the wilds.

<br>
Warforged<br>
Warforged, originally built as weapons for the Last War, are living constructs made of metal, wood, and stone, possessing sapience and emotion despite their mechanical nature, and now struggle to find purpose and identity in a world that no longer needs them for war.

<br>
Worg<br>
Worgs are intelligent, speech-capable predators with sharp senses and a deep bond to nature, often devoted to primal deities like the Devourer and the Fury, and while they lack hands, they can be outfitted with specialized armor and enchanted Steel Jaws to enhance their formidable bite.

<br>TipThe DM can provide you with more information on these species.<br><br>When choosing your species, consider the broader impact it has on your character's identity and how it ties into the world of Eberron. Reflect on these questions and ideas to deepen your understanding of your character’s heritage and how it influences their outlook and abilities:<br>
<br>Where do they come from?<br>
Every species in Eberron has a unique history and place in the world. How does your character's origin influence their perspective? Are they from a close-knit community like changelings who hide in plain sight, or a war-torn land like the goblinoids of Darguun?<br>

<br>What cultures, traditions, and beliefs have they inherited?<br>
Each species carries rich traditions, from the spiritual devotion of the kalashtar to the primal instincts of shifters. How do these cultural legacies shape your character’s worldview? Do they embrace their heritage or struggle against it?<br>

<br>How has their lineage prepared them to face the challenges ahead?<br>
Your character’s species affects their abilities and approach to obstacles. Do they draw on the resilience of their warforged construction, the fierce loyalty of a gnoll, or the adaptability of a changeling? Consider how your character’s species gives them unique advantages or creates challenges they must overcome.<br>

<br>How does the rarity of their species affect them?<br>
Eberron’s population is dominated by humans, dwarves, elves, halflings, and gnomes. If your character is a member of a rarer species—such as a medusa, warforged, or gnoll—how does this shape their interactions with others? Do they face prejudice, curiosity, or misunderstanding? How have they navigated life as an outsider, and do they try to blend in or embrace their uniqueness?
<br><br>Alignment represents your character’s moral and ethical stance in the world of Eberron, providing a framework for how they make decisions, interact with others, and approach challenges. However, unlike in more traditional D&amp;D settings, alignment in Eberron is not always black and white. The world is morally complex, and even the most righteous organizations, like the Church of the Silver Flame, have dark corners, while followers of sinister forces may act with kindness and honor.<br>DM RuleCharacters with an evil alignment are not allowed in this campaign.
Your character must be able to cooperate with the group and have motivations that fit the overall tone of the story. Consider creating a character who can work with others, even if they have different perspectives or goals.<br><br>In a setting shaped by intrigue, politics, and the aftermath of a devastating war, moral dilemmas are common. Characters may find themselves acting outside their alignment to achieve their goals or survive in a world where alliances shift and nothing is certain. Consider how your alignment might evolve as the story progresses.<br><br>
<br>
Lawful Good: A knight devoted to the Silver Flame, upholding justice but struggling with the darker actions of the church.

<br>
Neutral Good: A former soldier who seeks peace and healing in a war-torn world, but will break the rules to help those in need.

<br>
Chaotic Good: A daring bard who fights for freedom and equality, using their talents to inspire rebellion against corrupt rulers and oppressive systems.

<br>
Lawful Neutral: A Karrnathi officer who values order above all else, enforcing the law without concern for morality.

<br>
True Neutral: A druid of the Eldeen Reaches, focused on maintaining the balance of nature, indifferent to the politics and wars of nations.

<br>
Chaotic Neutral: A rogue changeling who lives by their own rules, adopting new identities and following the whims of the moment.

<br><br>Your alignment can influence how your character interacts with the world, as well as how NPCs or factions respond to them. While it doesn’t need to define every decision, it should guide your character’s general outlook. Consider the following questions as you choose your alignment:<br>
<br>What are your character’s personal morals?<br>
Do they value compassion, fairness, and honesty, or are they more concerned with self-preservation and ambition?<br>

<br>How do they view authority and rules?<br>
Does your character respect established laws and hierarchies, or do they prefer to challenge or ignore them in favor of personal freedom?<br>

<br>Will their alignment shift?<br>
Eberron’s morally complex world often pushes characters into difficult choices. Consider whether your character might undergo an alignment shift based on their experiences and the challenges they face.
<br><br>In Eberron, faith and belief systems are woven into everyday life and can deeply influence your character’s background, motivations, and development. Whether your character is a devoted follower of an established religion like the Silver Flame or the Sovereign Host, a member of a mysterious cult, or someone questioning their faith, your character’s connection to divine power—or lack thereof—can shape their path. As you build your character, consider how their beliefs align with their experiences and how these beliefs might evolve through the challenges they face in the world of Eberron.<br>TipThe DM can provide you with more extensive information on your religon<br><br>
<br>The Silver Flame: A tangible spiritual force that actively holds demons at bay. Followers of the Flame protect innocents from supernatural evil and encourage compassion. Think of it like a mix between the Jedi and the Men in Black — they draw power from the Flame to fight evil rather than worship an anthropomorphic god.
<br>The Blood of Vol: This is a practical, yet grim, faith that rejects the idea of an afterlife, viewing the gods as cruel. Followers believe that all mortals possess a spark of divinity within their blood, and Seeker clerics and paladins draw power from their own souls rather than deities.
<br>The Sovereign Host: A pantheon of deities whose presence is believed to guide their followers, though they don’t physically manifest in the world. This is the most popular religion in the Five Nations, and its casual faith asks little of its followers.
<br>The Dark Six: Representing chaos, greed, and destruction, the Dark Six are feared across Khorvaire. They embody the darker aspects of existence, such as war, betrayal, and wild nature, and are typically shunned by society. However, cults and outcasts may secretly revere them, believing that power can be gained by embracing these darker forces.
<br><br>
<br>The Cults of the Dragon Below: These cults serve dark, often malevolent powers or follow bizarre, irrational beliefs. While outsiders lump them together under this name, members of these cults see themselves as serving a higher purpose, such as the "blessed eye of the All-Seer" or "pilgrims of the Inner Sun." Many cults unknowingly serve ancient entities like the daelkyr or fiendish overlords, while others follow forces beyond mortal comprehension. Though they often clash with each other, each cult believes its cause is righteous. There are many cults to choose from, and your DM can offer more details to guide you in choosing one.
<br>Druid Sects: Druids in Eberron follow different sects, each with its own beliefs about nature, life, and the natural balance. These groups vary in purpose, from the Gatekeepers, who guard against extraplanar threats, to the Wardens of the Wood, protectors of the Eldeen Reaches. Druids can be found all across Eberron, from ancient forests to faraway planes, each sect offering a unique approach to the natural world. Your DM can provide more information on the sects that best fit your character.
<br>TipThe DM can provide you with more information about specific cults and sects.<br><br>
<br>Faithless: Many people in Eberron are faithless, either rejecting the existence of gods or simply not caring whether they exist since the gods do not manifest physically. If your character is faithless, consider whether they lost their belief after a traumatic event or never had faith to begin with.
<br><br>Your character’s faith, or lack thereof, can have significant implications for their interactions with others and how they view the world. In a setting like Eberron, where divine power is present yet the gods themselves remain distant, belief systems are a matter of choice and personal conviction rather than universal truth. Here are a few considerations:<br>
<br>
Social Connections: If your character follows an organized faith like the Silver Flame or the Sovereign Host, they may have connections with others who share their beliefs, from local temples to powerful religious organizations. This could offer support or lead to friction if your character's actions are at odds with the teachings of their faith.

<br>
Conflict and Rivalry: Some religions, such as the Silver Flame and the Blood of Vol, have contentious relationships with each other. Your character’s beliefs might place them in direct opposition to others—whether it's political tension, ideological debate, or outright hostility. Characters aligned with darker cults or the faithless might face mistrust or even persecution in more devout communities.

<br>
Moral Dilemmas: A character’s faith can guide their moral compass, influencing decisions in times of crisis. Does a follower of the Silver Flame prioritize the greater good, even if it involves difficult choices? Does a Seeker of the Blood of Vol hold their personal survival above all else? Your faith may also evolve, especially if your character experiences events that challenge their beliefs.

<br>
Divine or Supernatural Power: If your character is a cleric, druid, or paladin, their faith may provide direct access to divine or natural magic. But even non-religious characters may interact with or oppose divine forces. Your connection to a higher power (or the rejection of one) can play a major role in the abilities you gain and the challenges you face.

<br>
Cultural Identity: In Eberron, faith is often tied to culture. For instance, followers of the Sovereign Host might align with traditional values, while members of the Blood of Vol may question established norms. How does your character’s faith fit into their cultural heritage, and how does it shape their interactions with others from different belief systems?

<br><br>For most of the last century, the continent of Galifar was engulfed in a bitter civil war. If you’re human, you’ve never known a world without war. If you’re a warforged, you were literally built to fight in it. The Last War ended two years ago after the utter destruction of one of the warring nations.<br>Consider how the war shaped your character and their abilities. For instance, a rogue might have been a smuggler avoiding the war or an infiltrator working behind enemy lines.<br>Here are some key questions to help define your character’s wartime experience:<br>
<br>How were you involved in the war?    

<br>Were you a soldier, criminal, conscientious objector, or civilian?
<br>Did your talents keep you off the front lines, or were you directly involved in battle?
<br>In this magical world, wizards, artificers, and other classes all had roles on the battlefield. What was yours?


<br>If you fought, how did your service end?    

<br>Are you still in good standing with the military, or did you leave that life behind?
<br>Are you proud of your service, or would you rather forget it?
<br>Was there a defining moment, like a heroic battle or a narrow escape from death?


<br>How did the war affect you personally?    

<br>Did you lose a loved one or see your hometown destroyed?
<br>If you’re from Cyre, how has the loss of your entire nation shaped you?
<br>Did your wartime experiences challenge your faith, or did they strengthen it?


<br>TipYou don’t have to choose the "Soldier" Background just because you served in the war. <br><br>Your character's background represents the key aspects of their life before embarking on a path of adventure. It defines their skills, abilities, and life experiences, helping shape their personality and motivations. In this campaign, backgrounds offer flexibility, allowing you to choose from pre-existing ones or create a custom background that better fits Eberron’s unique setting.<br>DM RuleFor this campaign, you have two options:

<br>Pick a background from the PHB (Player's Handbook).
<br>Create a custom background using the format below.
<br><br>You can choose a background from Chapter 4 of the 2024 Player's Handbook and adapt it to suit Eberron's lore and your character's past.<br>When selecting a background from the PHB, you should:<br>
<br>alter the narrative details to explain your character’s background in the context of Eberron; and,
<br>for equipment, always choose the GP option.
<br><br>To make a truly personalized background, you can create one from scratch. This allows you to tailor every aspect of the character’s past to fit your story and make them feel uniquely tied to the Eberron setting.<br>Name:<br>
Start by giving your background a descriptive name that summarizes its theme (e.g., "Sharn Skyship Pilot" or "Dhakaani Historian").<br>Narrative:<br>
Write a short description explaining your character’s background in the context of Eberron. This should outline key life experiences or occupations relevant to the background.<br>Ability Scores:<br>
List three relevant ability scores. These should be justified by your background's narrative. <br>Feat:<br>
Pick an Origin Feat from chapter 5 of the 2024 Player's Handbook that suits your background. Explain why this feat is appropriate for your character’s past.<br>Skill Proficiencies:<br>
Select two skills tied to your background. Justify how your character developed these skills through their life experiences.<br>Tool Proficiency:<br>
Choose proficiency with one tool from chapter 6 of the PHB. Be sure to explain how this proficiency fits into your character's history.<br>Equipment:<br>
You get 50GP<br><br>Establishing meaningful character goals is a key element in shaping a dynamic, engaging campaign. These goals serve as the driving force behind your character’s actions, giving purpose to their journey and setting the stage for the adventures to come. As you build your character’s backstory and personality, you’ll also want to craft goals that reflect their ambitions, fears, and desires. To make the most of your character’s goals, consider framing them across three time scales: long-term, mid-term, and short-term.<br>DM RuleCreate a long-term goal, a couple medium term-goals, and a few short-term goals.<br><br>Long-term goals are the overarching objectives that define your character’s journey and often align with the broader story of the campaign. These goals are ambitious, sometimes life-changing, and could take the entirety of the campaign to achieve. Whether it's reclaiming a lost kingdom, seeking vengeance for a fallen comrade, or uncovering ancient secrets tied to the Prophecy, long-term goals give your character a central motivation. Think of these as the main arc of your character's story—something they’re striving towards as the ultimate expression of their desires or destiny.<br>
<br>Example: "I want to reclaim my family’s honor by proving our connection to the Silver Flame."
<br><br>Mid-term goals bridge the gap between the grand ambitions of long-term goals and the more immediate needs of short-term tasks. These goals take time and effort to achieve, often involving multiple steps, but they help move the character closer to their ultimate objectives. A mid-term goal might require you to gain allies, gather resources, or confront powerful enemies along the way. They also provide key moments of character development, as your character grows and changes while working towards these milestones.<br>
<br>Example: "I need to find the sacred relic of my ancestors in order to unlock the true power of my family’s lineage."
<br><br>Short-term goals are immediate, actionable objectives that can typically be accomplished in a session or two. These are practical tasks your character might focus on as stepping stones toward their larger goals. Short-term goals might involve acquiring a specific item, solving a local problem, or getting closer to an important NPC. These goals keep the character active and involved in the day-to-day progression of the story while steadily advancing their broader aspirations.<br>
<br>Example: "I need to track down the local historian who might have a clue about the relic’s location."
<br><br>When creating goals, it’s important to ensure they are both achievable and fun to pursue. A good goal is measurable—your character should know when they’ve succeeded or failed. This clarity allows the game master to design challenges and opportunities that align with your goals. Additionally, goals should have consequences for failure, whether it’s personal loss, a setback in the campaign, or changes in the world around you. This adds weight to your character’s choices and actions, making the game more immersive.<br>
<br>Achievability: A goal like "I want to become the most powerful wizard" is vague and hard to measure. A clearer goal would be, "I want to defeat an archmage in a duel to prove my mastery of magic."
<br>Consequences: A failed goal could mean the loss of allies, the rise of a rival faction, or even damage to your character’s reputation or resources. This adds stakes to your decisions.
<br><br>As you set goals, think about how they might intersect with other characters in the party. Shared objectives or parallel paths can strengthen the group’s cohesion and create opportunities for collaborative storytelling. Goals don’t need to be identical, but they should complement each other, helping the party work toward common aims while allowing for individual character arcs. Discuss your goals with the group and explore how they can tie into the campaign’s larger narrative.<br><br>Your character’s goals will influence not only their personal journey but also how they interact with the world and other characters. Setting strong, clear goals helps drive the campaign forward, guiding your character’s actions and decisions. Here are some potential implications to consider:<br>
<br>Story Development: Your goals can provide natural story hooks for the DM, allowing them to weave your personal arc into the broader campaign. Whether you’re chasing lost artifacts, seeking revenge, or working to redeem a fallen house, these goals can become central plot points.
<br>Party Dynamics: Your goals might align or clash with those of other party members. This can lead to cooperation, conflict, or even intrigue within the group, depending on how closely your objectives align with the party’s collective mission.
<br>Motivation for Adventure: Clear goals give your character a reason to stay engaged in the campaign. They provide personal stakes, ensuring that your character has a vested interest in the outcome of missions and adventures. These motivations might shift over time as goals are achieved or new opportunities arise.
<br>Character Growth: Your character’s goals will evolve as they grow through the campaign. Long-term goals might shift, or new priorities might emerge based on what happens in the story. Achieving or failing at a goal can lead to personal development, changing your character’s outlook or shaping their future ambitions.
<br><br>As you create your backstories, think about whether your characters have existing connections with one another. These connections aren’t required, but you're free to explore whether your characters have crossed paths before given the context of the starting of the campaign.<br>Some examples might be,<br>
<br>Shared experiences during the Last War: If any characters served together or found themselves on the same side, consider what they went through and how it shaped their relationship. Did they bond over a difficult situation, or was their time together marked by tension?
<br>Unresolved debts or favors: Maybe one character owes another a debt or favor from a past encounter. This could be financial, personal, or something more abstract. How does this unresolved matter affect their current relationship?
<br>Family ties or common origins: Perhaps your characters come from the same town, share a family connection, or belong to a similar cultural background. How did they know each other before the campaign, and what’s brought them together again?
<br>Professional or personal history: Characters might have crossed paths professionally or personally in the past. Maybe they worked together, shared an adventure, or had a brief encounter. Was their previous experience positive, or did it end on uncertain terms?
]]></description><link>dm\sessions\session-0\5.-developing-your-backstory.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">DM/Sessions/Session 0/5. Developing Your Backstory.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 11:52:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[6. Getting Started]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>To kick off our Eberron campaign, we’ll be using a two-part "Session Zero" to lay the foundation for both the story and your characters. These sessions will help set clear expectations, make sure everyone’s comfortable with the gameplay, and give you everything you need to create characters that feel right at home in the world of Eberron.<br>Here’s how it will work:<br>
<br>In the first session, we’ll go over the campaign guidelines, dive into the unique lore of Eberron, and start discussing your character concepts.
<br>Afterward, you’ll have a bit of homework—fleshing out your backstory, figuring out your character’s goals, and thinking about how they fit into the group.
<br>When we meet for the second session, we’ll finalize your characters, introduce the starting hook for the campaign, and make sure everyone is ready to jump into the adventure.
<br><br><br>
<br>
Establish Guidelines and Expectations  

<br>Set overall campaign rules and group expectations for gameplay, boundaries, and conduct.
<br>Establish a schedule


<br>
Introduction to Eberron    

<br>Overview of Eberron’s unique setting, including its rich lore, history, diverse locations, and inhabitants.
<br>Overview of how your characters will begin in the campaign.


<br>
Character Creation Discussion

<br>Explore the key aspects of your character’s backstory.
<br>Collaborate and discuss potential character concepts and how they may interact in the story.


<br><br>
<br>Everyone understands the group's expectations, boundaries, rules, and dynamics.
<br>Players have a foundational understanding of Eberron to begin shaping their characters.
<br>The group has an open discussion about character ideas and possible party roles.
<br>By the end of the session, players should have chosen their class and species, and have the groundwork to begin developing their backstory.
<br><br><br>When choosing your class, it's important to select something that excites you while ensuring the group has a balanced mix of roles. A well-rounded party can handle various challenges more effectively. Discuss with your group to make sure there’s a good spread of abilities, whether it's tanking, healing, sneaking, or dealing massive damage. While it's not necessary to fill every role perfectly, having a diverse set of skills helps cover all the bases and makes the group more adaptable to different situations.<br>Consider these categories:<br>
- Tank/Front-Line Fighter: Absorbs damage and holds enemies back (Barbarian, Fighter, Paladin).<br>
- Healer/Support: Keeps the party alive and buffs allies (Cleric, Druid, Bard).<br>
- Explorer/Investigator: Specializes in sneaking, traps, and finding secrets (Rogue, Ranger).<br>
- Magic-User/Glass Cannon: Deals high damage with spells but is fragile (Wizard, Sorcerer, Warlock).<br>
- Face: Excels in social encounters and negotiation (Bard, Paladin, Sorcerer).<br><br>DM RuleDO NOT select any starting equipment. You will have gold from both your class and your background. Record this on your player sheet for now.
You MAY select a starting trinket.<br><br>DM RuleYour characters are NOT dragonmarked<br><br><br>For homework, players will develop their character backstories by exploring the following elements:<br>
<br>Choosing Your Class: Select the class that defines your character’s abilities and role in the world.
<br>Choosing Your Species: Choose a species that shapes your character’s culture, history, and worldview.
<br>Choosing Your Alignment: Decide on an alignment that reflects your character’s moral compass while fitting with the group dynamics.
<br>Exploring Faith and Beliefs: Determine the role of religion or philosophy in your character’s life and their connection to Eberron’s many belief systems.
<br>Your Role in the Last War: Reflect on how the Last War affected your character and their journey after the conflict.
<br>Selecting Or Creating a Background: Build or select a background that summarizes your character’s experiences and the skills they’ve gained.
<br>Establishing Character Goals: Set long-term, mid-term, and short-term goals that will drive your character’s actions and decisions.
<br>Determining Connections with Other Characters: Explore potential relationships and shared histories with other party members to create a cohesive group.
<br><br>
<br>Players have had time to thoughtfully develop their backstories and characters.
<br>Players are ready to discuss and share their character concepts with the group at the next session.
<br>Players are excited and eager to start the campaign with a strong understanding of their character’s motivations and role in the story.
<br><br><br>
<br>Introduce Your Character: Share the backstory you’ve developed, highlighting the key points that define who your character is, their motivations, and why they are part of this adventure.
<br>Determine Ability Scores: We’ll finalize your character’s ability scores using one of the methods outlined in the 2024 Player’s Handbook—either standard array, point buy, or rolling.
<br>Get the Hook: We’ll introduce the campaign’s starting hook, setting the stage for how the characters come together and begin their shared adventure.
<br>Fill in the Details: Together, we’ll complete your character sheets by selecting equipment, filling in any missing features, and finalizing the last touches that bring your character to life.
<br><br>
<br>
<br>Ensure all players are comfortable with their characters' abilities, background, and place within the group dynamic.
<br>Double-check that everyone’s character goals and connections align with the overall story.
<br>Ensure each player understands how their character fits into the opening of the campaign and how they might interact with the rest of the party.
]]></description><link>dm\sessions\session-0\6.-getting-started.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">DM/Sessions/Session 0/6. Getting Started.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 23:24:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hook]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="Image - Newsroom of the Korranberg Chronicle.webp" src="lib\media\image-newsroom-of-the-korranberg-chronicle.webp"><br>The Korranberg Chronicle newsroom buzzes with the frantic energy of a city that never sleeps. Quills scratch feverishly across parchment, the steady clacking of arcane typewriters creating a constant rhythm. The scent of warm Zilargo coffee wafts through the room, mingling with the sharp tang of fresh ink and the faint ozone of everbright lanterns flickering overhead.<br>The newsroom itself is a chaotic mosaic of movement—runners darting between desks, laden with hastily scrawled messages and half-rolled scrolls, while editors bark orders over the din, their voices sharp and cutting like the crack of a whip. Each desk is cluttered with piles of parchment, crumpled drafts, and arcane devices—small enchanted stones humming with the magic of distant correspondents reporting from the far corners of Khorvaire. Scribes transcribe messages sent through speaking stones, while arcane bells ring with incoming news from across the continent.<br>Eyes follow as you and a few other unfamiliar faces are led by a discreet and efficient warforged assistant, its brass-plated body gleaming in the everbright light as it ushers you forward with polite but firm gesture to the office of Thalia ir'Zannath, the Chronicle’s sharp-eyed and stern editor. Each of you was summoned, quite unexpectedly, by a terse message from Thalia herself. <br>aside: The prefix "ir'" in her name, a subtle yet telling marker of nobility in Eberron. The "ir'" denotes that she hails from a noble family, part of the old bloodlines that still hold sway in the Five Nations. Though nobility in Eberron doesn't always equate to vast power or riches, it often comes with influence and a sense of duty to one's house. Thalia, however, seems more focused on her role at the Chronicle than on leveraging her title, choosing to wield her influence through stories and uncovering the truth rather than through courtly politics. Keep in mind, her noble background may also afford her connections and resources that a common editor wouldn’t have.<br>QuestionAt this point, feel free to describe how your character reacts to the chaos of the newsroom. Are they curious? Nervous? Eager? Or perhaps frustrated at being pulled into something without explanation? Do they say anything to the others as you're escorted through the Chronicle?<br>You push past a blur of faces all flushed with the thrill of the next big scoop. Somewhere near the back, a dwarven journalist can be heard grumbling about a botched story from the Mror Holds, while a gnome hurriedly sketches a political cartoon that depicts a scandal among the Dragonmarked Houses. The Chronicle is a living, breathing beast, hungry for stories, and you can feel its pulse in the very walls of the building.<br><img alt="Image - Thalia ir'Zannath in her office.webp" src="lib\media\image-thalia-ir'zannath-in-her-office.webp"><br>As you reach Thalia ir'Zannath's office, the noise fades—though the energy doesn’t.<br>
Her office is a cluttered sanctuary in the storm. The half-elf editor sits behind a desk overflowing with old editions of the Chronicle, rolled-up maps, and notes scribbled on everything from parchment scraps to napkins. A great iron globe of Eberron hangs suspended in the air beside her, rotating slowly, its surface etched with pins marking stories in distant lands. One wall is dominated by a towering bookshelf, crammed with dusty tomes, journals, and research materials, all barely held together by a tangle of red ribbons used for cross-referencing. Across from it, a large, detailed map of Khorvaire sprawls across the wall, covered in ink marks and hastily pinned notes marking key locations in the city. It's a testament to Thalia's obsession with finding stories in every corner of the city of towers.<br>She thanks the warforged with a curt nod as it quietly slips out of the room. "Close the door," she says, her voice carrying the same authority that keeps the newsroom in check. She gestures for you all to sit as she leans forward, fingers tapping thoughtfully on the desk.<br>QuestionAt this point, feel free to describe how your character enters and takes their seat. Are they confident? Reluctant? Curious about the others in the room? This is your chance to introduce yourselves to each other, even briefly. Do you ask each other any questions?<br>“You’re probably wondering why I called you here—and why you’re sitting with people you’ve never met,” Thalia begins, her gaze shifting between you. “We don’t usually throw our reporters into danger, but you’re not just reporters, are you?”<br>She pauses, letting the tension hang in the air for a moment before continuing. “The Chronicle has a knack for recognizing talent, for finding those with something...extra. In a world as dangerous as Eberron, we need more than just sharp minds and quick pens—we need people with innate abilities, people who can handle more than just words.” Her eyes narrow, her voice growing more intense. “People like you.”<br>You exchange glances with the others.<br>She continues, "Eberron is a world on edge, still haunted by the lingering tensions of the Last War. While most people go about their lives, unaware of the dangers lurking beneath the surface, there are some—like you—who are different. Who have the power to face those dangers head-on. From the fanatics of the Emerald Claw to the cults of the Dragon Below, to the far-reaching plots of the daelkyr and ancient archfiends, Eberron is a world in need of heroes. And the Chronicle? Well, the Chronicle knows where to find them."<br>Thalia leans forward, her voice taking on a tone both earnest and knowing as she pulls a thick dossier from her desk and places it gently before you. Her sharp green eyes scan the room, pausing on each of you with an intensity that feels less like an appraisal and more like a recognition. "You’ve been selected to join the The Lantern Bearers, a special group here at the Chronicle. A group who sheds light on the hidden truths of the world, guiding the way like a beacon of hope and knowledge--a group of our most elite" she says, her voice steady and sincere. "The Chronicle has always been more than just a newspaper. We don’t just report the news—we uncover the truth, no matter the cost. And some stories... well, some stories are too dangerous, too extraordinary, for ordinary reporters."<br>She taps the dossier, her expression softening slightly as she continues. "That’s why we created the The Lanterns Bearer—a special task force of individuals with the talent and drive to not only report on the world’s most mysterious and dangerous events but to face them head-on. You see, the Chronicle has been watching you since you first walked through our doors. We've seen your courage, your instincts, your unique abilities. We've known, all along, that you had something more to offer. That's why you’re here today."<br>She lets her words sink in for a moment before continuing, leaning in just a little closer. "The Lantern Bearers aren’t just journalists—they’re investigators, explorers, protectors. They go where others won’t and tackle stories that could change the course of nations—or reveal secrets that some would rather stay buried. But the Lantern Bearers don’t work alone. When a crisis or mystery demands it, we form what we call a Dispatch—a group of Lantern Bearers brought together to take on the most dangerous assignments, to protect the truth and make sure the wrong hands never grasp it. Today, you are that Dispatch."<br>QuestionThalia pauses, glancing between you all with a hint of a smile. Do you have questions? Concerns? Now is your chance to ask her about the mission, the Lantern Bearers, or why you were chosen.<br>Thalia pauses, glancing between you all with a hint of a smile. "Each of you has been chosen not just for your skill with words but for something deeper. There are forces at play in Eberron that threaten to tip the balance—ancient magics, secretive factions, and powers most can’t even imagine. You’ve shown the kind of resolve and talent needed to confront those dangers. Together, as this newly-formed Dispatch, you’ll uncover secrets, navigate threats, and bring back the stories that truly matter."<br>She gestures to the dossier again, her voice now filled with purpose. "This is your first assignment.<br>Thalia leans back, her gaze warm yet firm. "I’m not here to force you into anything. But understand this: the Chronicle doesn’t pick its Lantern Bearers lightly. You’ve been watched because we believe in you, because we’ve seen that spark in you that’s needed to make a difference in this world. This is your chance to not only write history but to protect it. And as part of this Dispatch, you’ll be standing on the front lines of the stories that matter most."<br>She offers a small, knowing smile. "So the question isn’t whether you’re ready—you’ve been ready longer than you know. The question is whether you're willing to take this step, to embrace the role the Chronicle believes you were meant for."<br>QuestionHow does your character respond? Are they eager to jump in, or are they cautious? How do they feel about being watched all this time? This is your moment to decide how your character reacts and what they choose to say or ask next.<br><br> The Professor at Morgrave University, the one who claims to have found an ancient schema beneath Sharn? It’s more than just another academic discovery—it could unlock secrets that have the potential to reshape the world. And there are others interested in getting their hands on it—House Cannith, the Emerald Claw, and who knows what else. We need people like you, with the ability to handle the kind of situations that no ordinary reporter could survive."<br>She stands up, pacing behind her desk, her voice quickening with excitement. “Today’s story might be the biggest one yet. Professor Garthen Daela at Morgrave University claims to have discovered something ancient buried beneath the city—an old schema from before Galifar, potentially tied to the creation of the warforged. If it’s real, it could change everything we know about magic and artifice. But we’re not the only ones interested. House Cannith is already sniffing around, and there are whispers that the Emerald Claw has taken notice.”<br>Thalia stops in front of the large map of Sharn, tapping a location near the Crystal Bridge Ward. “You’ve been selected because you’re not just normal reporters—you’re part of the Vanguard. And right now, we need your skills, your abilities, and your instincts. This isn’t just about getting the story. It’s about protecting something that could reshape the future of Khorvaire.”<br>She slides the dossier closer to you, filled with rough sketches of the artifact, notes on Professor Daela’s research, and potential contacts within the underbelly of Sharn. “Your job is to meet with Daela, head down into the sewers, and retrieve the schema. You’ll be going places even the Sharn Watch won’t venture. You’ll be facing more than just rats and thieves—there’s magic down there, old and dangerous.”<br>Thalia pauses, a slight smile tugging at the corners of her mouth. “But you’ve been chosen because you can handle it. The Chronicle has faith in you. We don’t just report the news—we uncover the truth, and sometimes, we protect it.”<br>She reaches into a drawer and pulls out three delicate mechanical birds—each one a small, intricate homunculus with crystal-tipped wings that shimmer in the light of the everbright lanterns. “Zephyr, Boreas, and Mistral. These homunculi will keep us in touch. Just speak your message into the gem and they’ll find their way back to me, no matter where you are in Sharn. Send updates, warnings, or your final story—whatever it takes.”<br>Thalia fixes you with a final, piercing look. “This is your first assignment as part of the Vanguard. Make sure it counts. The Chronicle’s reputation, and your lives, are riding on this. Go out there, make history—and keep your wits about you. In Sharn, danger lurks around every corner, especially when the stakes are this high.”]]></description><link>dm\sessions\session-0\hook.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">DM/Sessions/Session 0/Hook.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 11:50:25 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\image-newsroom-of-the-korranberg-chronicle.webp" length="0" type="image/webp"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib\media\image-newsroom-of-the-korranberg-chronicle.webp"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Session 0]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br><a data-href="0. Rules and Expectations" href="dm\sessions\session-0\0.-rules-and-expectations.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">0. Rules and Expectations</a>
<br><a data-href="1. Welcome to Eberron" href="dm\sessions\session-0\1.-welcome-to-eberron.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">1. Welcome to Eberron</a>
<br><a data-href="2. Eberron's History" href="dm\sessions\session-0\2.-eberron's-history.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">2. Eberron's History</a>
<br><a data-href="3. Eberron's Places" href="dm\sessions\session-0\3.-eberron's-places.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">3. Eberron's Places</a>
<br><a data-href="4. Eberron's People" href="dm\sessions\session-0\4.-eberron's-people.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">4. Eberron's People</a>
<br><a data-href="5. Developing Your Backstory" href="dm\sessions\session-0\5.-developing-your-backstory.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">5. Developing Your Backstory</a>
<br><a data-href="6. Getting Started" href="dm\sessions\session-0\6.-getting-started.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">6. Getting Started</a>
<br><a data-href="Hook" href="dm\sessions\session-0\hook.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hook</a>
<br>]]></description><link>dm\sessions\session-0\session-0.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">DM/Sessions/Session 0/Session 0.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 11:47:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to Eberron]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>ImportantWelcome to Eberron, a world where ancient magic pulses through the land, mysteries lie hidden in every shadow, and epic adventures await those brave enough to seek them.<br><br>Our journey begins with some initial planning to shape the kind of game and adventure we want to experience. We'll think about the type of campaign, the dynamics of our adventuring party, and how these elements will blend to create an unforgettable story.<br>To get started, head over to the Session "-1" (Preparation) section to get yourself ready for the adventure ahead.<br><br>]]></description><link>home.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Home.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Percival]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 23:26:14 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>